We can all quiet down.
The event is going to begin.
My name is Olivia.
I work here at Or Books, and I do the events and publicity.
And we're really excited to have our wonderful
panelists and authors and journalists and activists
here today, philosophers, for one part of our
series called Live on Avenue C at Or Books.
Tonight, our event is honor of the release of this
wonderful book, which is for sale at the front of the bar.
Deluge, of which both Muin and Coulter are contributors.
Unfortunately, Jamie, the editor,
is not able to make it tonight, but Razia, our wonderful moderator,
will open with some remarks by him.
And we hope you come to more of our wonderful or events.
The next one is on May 15th for another
one of our books, Corporate Coup.
But for now, I'll turn it over,
And thank you so much to our panelists and
moderator and all of you for being here tonight.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Thank you, Olivia.
Thank you, Colin, as well.
And thank you very much for coming, everyone.
And thank you to everyone who is joining us online.
For just a moment, if you can imagine that I
am Jamie Stern-Viner, the editor of this book.
This is his opening remarks.
He's sorry that he can't be here.
So, I'd like to begin by thanking Olivia
from All Books for organizing this
meeting, Razia for chairing to me,
and all the panelists for taking part.
This is a somber event, as book launches go,
but then it's a somber book and a somber moment.
According to the latest humanitarian reports, Israel has killed
more than 33,000 people in Gaza, mostly women and children.
has partially or totally destroyed more than 60% of all houses in Gaza.
And a deliberately engineered famine
is imminent, if not already underway.
In October, the UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres observed
that this catastrophe, quote, did not happen in a vacuum.
This week, the heroic UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestinian refugees,
UNRWA, noted that the crisis now unfolding there is unparalleled.
Both these statements are true.
What's happening in Gaza is the product of
long-standing, multi-layered injustices.
That is to say, decades after decade of
dispossession, annexation, siege and massacre.
And the current catastrophe has also,
in critical respects, broken new ground.
With this book I have tried to to illuminate
both the continuities and the chambers
in what's unfolding in Gaza, to provide
readers with the crucial background context
necessary to understand how things came to
this horrific past, while also providing
an initial analysis of what looks set to be
a turning point in the conflict's history.
Colter Lewers's chapter in the book, based on his doctoral dissertation,
runs through the whole diplomatic background to the conflict since 1967.
He authoritatively demonstrates that Israel had chance
after chance to resolve the conflict on reasonable
terms, first with the Palestine Liberation Organisation
and then after its election in 2006 with hundreds.
In my view it's because Israel and its international enablers
spurned these opportunities that we are where we are today.
Muhin Rabbani's contribution situates the
Gaza war within two crucial regional dynamics.
The warming ties between Israel and the Gulf States
facilitated and encouraged by the United States on one hand
and on the other hand, relations between Hamas and the
so-called Axis of Resistance led by Iran and Hezbollah.
Among the most heart-rending passages
in the book are Muhin's descriptions
of the hapless US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, shuttling
between Arab governments, cap in hand, begging them to help bail Israel
out, only to return with nothing but that broken, dead-eyed stare.
Norman Finkelstein and Slavoj Zizek, of
course, need no introduction from me.
I merely take this opportunity to thank both for their participation
and to extend a special thanks to Norman for his help with the book
and for his exemplary life's work standing
for truth and justice come what may.
Beyond the appalling devastation in Gaza,
there is a real possibility now that the
conflict will escalate to set the whole region
on fire and the rest of the world with it.
The stakes here could not be higher.
And so I am glad now to hand over to a panel that could
scarcely be better equipped to help guide us through it.
Thank you.
And our thanks to Jamie.
Just to give you a quick structure of how we're going to proceed,
each of the panelists is going to speak for about six or seven minutes
to present what they would like to say about the current crisis.
And then we will, the five of us have a discussion.
Then we will open it up to questions on the floor and
possibly also some questions for the audience online.
I just want to add one other thing before
we begin to add to what Jamie has said.
The numbers that we are presented with every day seem unfathomable.
Today is Eid al-Fitr.
Eid Mubarak to those who are celebrating and
also to those who actually can't celebrate.
And because the numbers are so unfathomable,
I want all of us, if we can, to keep in the backs of
our mind that every life
is a whole world, every life.
And so when we're faced with these enormous numbers,
that's the thing that I would like us
to think about while we're absorbing
the political analysis, the potential ramifications still to come.
Thank you very much, all of you, for being here tonight.
We're going to start with Colter,
who has, of course, published in this book.
Okay, thank you, Razia.
In recent weeks, the Joe Biden administration has
claimed that once the current crisis in Gaza is over,
it's going to revive, quote, unquote, concerted efforts at
establishing a two-state resolution to the Israel-Palestine conflict.
It's been all the more vehement, however, that there
is no place for Hamas in this two-state settlement.
You know the argument.
Hamas is committed to destroying the state of Israel.
Therefore, Hamas itself must be destroyed.
Therefore, the genocide in Gaza must continue
if we ever want to see any peace in the region.
Claims like this, blaming the Palestinian leadership for the
Israel-Palestine conflicts infamous intractability are of course not new.
Decades ago, the Israeli foreign minister, Aba Eben,
claimed that, quote, the Palestinian leadership has never
missed an opportunity to miss an opportunity for peace.
Now as my chapter in Deluge attempts to demonstrate,
now the main problem with this claim is that it's
completely contradicted by the factual record.
In reality, both the Palestine Liberation
Organization, the PLO, and then after at Hamas
have, with varying degrees of clarity, endorsed
a two-state resolution to the conflict,
whereas Israel, of course backed unilaterally by the United States
has persistently rejected such a resolution in favor of territorial
expansion and has in fact resorted often to very bloody military
assaults in order to derail the threat of Palestinian peace offensives.
If you take the PLO in the aftermath
of the June 1967 war, the PLO initially
rejected recognition of Israel for perfectly understandable reasons.
did not want to accept a state that had been
established on 78% of historic Palestine
via the dispossession and displacement
of the indigenous Palestinian people.
And yet from the early 1970s, particularly after the October 1973
war, Yasser Arafat and the core Palestinian leadership recognized that
legitimizing Palestinian claims in the eyes of the international
community would necessitate the
pragmatic step of recognizing Israel.
And already in January of 1976, the PLO offered to
do just that at the United Nations Security Council.
Predictably, the United States reacted by vetoing the resolution.
Israel, for its part, refused to take
part in the Security Council deliberations
and carried out airstrikes in Lebanon
against Palestinian refugees, killing dozens.
And as this pattern of Israeli behavior became
more and more manifest in the late 1970s,
American officials came to observe that Israeli strikes in South
Lebanon had very little to do with
the supposed threat of Palestinian
terror, and in fact everything to do with attempting to batter
the Palestinians out of their moderation and back into extremism.
The apex of this strategy was of course the
June 1982 Israeli invasion of Lebanon in which,
for fear of the fact that the Palestine
Liberation Organization had accepted a ceasefire
and strupulously adhered to it for over a
year and that was advocating negotiations once
again, Israel steamrolled into Lebanon, killing
15,000 to 20,000 Palestinians and Lebanese.
Skip ahead 25 years, and Israel's today, or
not today, but in 2006 and after, carried out
the exact same plague book in relation to
its, to the threat of Hamas peace offensives.
Elected in January 2006 on a reform platform, Hamas very
quickly signaled to Washington that it was willing to
abandon its notorious 1988 charter and to integrate
itself into negotiations aimed at a two-state settlement.
The crucial point is this.
In the 15 years since, neither Washington or Tel Aviv has ever once so
much as indicated that it would be willing to test that Hamas offer.
To the contrary, they immediately moved to punish the Hamas leadership
and the people of Gaza through that vile and illegal blockade.
When Hamas threatened to break with its assigned role as
a rejectionist terrorist group and sought to integrate
itself into negotiations, Israel furthermore fell back upon
its age-old method, a massive resort to military violence.
And as Norman has documented in insane detail, it
carried out military operations in 2006, in 2008, in
2012, and 2014, in virtually every case, aimed at least
in part at derailing Palestinian peace initiatives.
And so when the question is raised,
how can Israel coexist with Hamas when it refuses to engage in
diplomatic activity refuses to recognize Israel, the simple answer
is that Hamas tried. It tried that for 15 years and every avenue
it sought to go down, it was blocked by American and Israeli power.
And as I write in the chapter, the bottom
line is this, that it were it not for the fact
that Israel not only missed but actively
spurned and sabotaged, spurned and sabotaged
every Palestinian peace offer, those crimes
crimes committed on October 7th, and the much
greater crime that is ongoing, that Israeli
genocide in Gaza, would never have happened.
They would never have happened because the
Israel-Palestine conflict would have long been resolved.
Thank you very much.
Let's turn now to Muin Rabban.
Thank you very much, Raziel, and thank you to OR Books
for organizing this event and inviting me to participate.
think this is one we're supposed to wave the book around.
And I would particularly refer you to not only Walter's outstanding
chapter, but also Janie's brilliant introduction to that book.
My chapter was about, sorry, yeah, I'll speak closer to the mic.
Yes, I'll speak You've also put the line. My chapter
was about the regional dynamics of the current crisis.
And given time constraints, I'd like to focus on an issue that most
insta pundits who have emerged out of the woodworks since October 7,
what for them has been an article of faith, which is
that a primary motivation for Hamas to launch its attacks
on Israel on October 7 was to sabotage the prospect
of an imminent Israeli-Saudi normalization agreement.
And I'd like to explain why this was not the case, and that we
should not take these instabundants any more seriously when they
were pontificating about Ukraine, before that about COVID and
other issues on which they reinvent themselves every few months.
A key issue is that the discussions were not really about
an Israeli-Saudi normalization agreement in the sense
that there would be an agreement where Israel and Saudi
Arabia would make their primary concessions to each other.
Rather, the discussion was about an Israeli-Saudi-US agreement
where the key commitments were being made by the United States.
And the key commitments the United States was making were
to Saudi Arabia, specifically in the form of a security
guarantee to Saudi Arabia and in the form of the delivery
of a nuclear reactor with enrichment capabilities.
And that alone should tell you that such an agreement
was extremely unlikely from the outset, because those
are commitments that the United States could only have
implemented if it had obtained congressional approval.
And for a variety of reasons that I won't
get into here, it was extremely unlikely
that Congress would have gone along with
such formal US commitments to Saudi Arabia.
Secondly, Israel would be required to make a number of gestures
to the Palestinians in the context of such an agreement.
And although the gestures were largely of
a cosmetic nature, we were dealing with an
Israeli government that is incapable of making
even cosmetic gestures to the Palestinians.
And I think the Biden administration at some level was
hoping that this would induce the Israeli Prime Minister
Netanyahu to alter his governing position and switch out
some of the neo-fascist right parties for more centrist ones.
The problem there is that Israel's most prominent opposition leader,
Yair Al-Bibt, has been on record repeatedly stating that he would not
endorse any normalization agreement with with Saudi Arabia that involved
an American commitment to deliver a nuclear reactor to Saudi Arabia.
So my first point is that such an agreement
was in any case extremely unlikely.
My second point is that even if I'm wrong and such
an agreement had been
imminent and if Hamas had
been imminent, such an agreement was about to be
signed, it would have made no sense for them to
launch this attack in order to sabotage such an
agreement because if we look at the history of
Arab-Israeli normalization agreements there is no
record of such normalization agreements being reversed
or suspended or abrogated on account of Israeli
policy towards the Palestinians so if you take the
main one the 1979 Egyptian-Israeli peace treaty it
was essentially unaffected by not only continuing
Israeli expansionism in the West Bank and the Gaza
Strip, but even wasn't affected by Israel's 1982
invasion of Lebanon that Golta referred to, or
the Saba Shatima massacres at their culmination.
Similarly, the Jordanian-Israeli peace treaty of 1994 was
unaffected by subsequent Israeli policy, including its
brutal repression of Palestinians during the Second
Intifada, and the more recent grandiloquently named Abraham
Accords that were midwifed by Prince Jared Kushner during
the Trump administration were unaffected by, first of all,
the conflict that erupted in 2021, or
indeed by the current crisis in civil
genocidal assault on the Gaza Strip.
In other words, the most Hamas could have
hoped to achieve would have been a decent enter to postpone a Saudi-Israeli
normalization agreement by a decent
interval, the corpses were buried and so on.
And I think it's fair to conclude that the Hamas leadership would
have concluded that that would simply not have been with the effort.
And indeed, if we look at Hamas' statements on October
7th and since then, they put out one major statement
a few months ago in which they sought to explain and
justify and rationalize the attacks of October 7th.
They don't mention Saudi Arabia even once, or the
prospects of a Saudi-Israeli normalization of it even once.
They do talk about regional and international neglect
and marginalization of the Taliban question, but
in a much broader sense than in terms of any specific
agreements that they were hoping to sabotage.
Am I out of time?
I've just got a minute.
So my final observation would be that, yes,
this regional and international marginalization and the left of
the question of Palestine and using Arab-Israeli normalization
to oppose Palestinian rights rather than as leverage for
Palestinian rights did factor into it in a general sense.
And that also explains, I think, why there
has been so little regional and international
response to Israel's genocide was sold against
the Gaza Strip going on now for over half a year.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Slavoj Žižek.
Okay.
First, I must emphasize how proud I am to be
here, and sorry if I begin with you, Norman.
I think it will sound pathetic, but I mean
it literally, that the existence of people
like you is the best argument against antisemitism.
It's not that people like you unexist.
Let me go on.
I would like to briefly report on you
on my pretty terrifying inner shock.
Maybe some of you know about it, but it happened in Europe.
At Stanford, I opened a book, a book fair.
Slovenia was the guest of honor, so I was
allowed to speak at the opening ceremony.
My speech was, I'm almost ashamed of it,
so absolutely careful, moderated and so on.
I said, yes, I condemn Hamas, everything.
My point was just Palestinians are also suffering.
You know what happened?
They have now a special position in every German land called
beyond factor to cut it short commissar for fighting antisemitism.
And he and another two politicians go to YouTube, you can find
it, stood up and like in old communist times, but communists know
it better, stood up and started
to shout at me, I'm anti-Semitic,
I am equalizing blah, blah, blah, Hamas, and I'm the worst thing.
I'm contextualizing it.
And then there was a series of attacks in big German
newspapers on me, Frankfurter Allgemeine and so on.
The title of one of them is very clear.
Hamas has no context.
Like it's literally, you have to understand this,
you have to go back to German idealism metaphysics.
The idea is this is absolute original abyssal evil.
No context can
even explain it.
And when I then quoted as a reply, Primo
Levi of all guys, who said it's crucial to
analyze Holocaust, not to say this is just
evil, I was again attacked, blah, blah.
So let me not use, let me not lose time.
Another important thing happened there.
I was accused of politicizing the event, book fair,
oh, this is a pure cultural event, blah, blah.
For me, there were five speakers from Germany, all of them openly
repeated one motive, full
unconditional support for Israel.
I just added to it, Palestinians are also suffering.
I was accused of politicizing kids.
And this brings me to what goes on today, yesterday in Israel.
You know, Anad Mattar, the professor of philosophy there, is now a very sad
thing, because she made some for
Israel-established and problematic statements.
Okay, they want to fire her at the
university, but two things are ominous here.
First, students protested against her.
I think the same thing I noticed in Reagan's time when I visited Berkeley,
professors were usually old 68 guys, much more progressive than students.
And I don't know how it is here, but all around Europe, the younger
generation of men mostly is getting absolutely more reactionary.
The other thing, Anab Matath's thesis that
every ethics is grounded in a political decision
is fully justified here, because, you see, what
happened in France when they claim, no, the
first guys who preach total support from Israel,
this was totally apolitical, just compassion
and so on and so on, no, such depoliticization
of judgment is politics at its dirtiest.
Let me go on.
The fiasco of German philosophy as an answer to all
these attacks in the corner with them against me, Jurgen
Habermas, as close as you can come to a German state
philosopher and two other of his followers wrote a
public letter, they don't mention me, but I have my KGB
agents there, against me claiming, no, unconditional,
you know, the usual bullshit, Israel the only democratic
society in the Middle East and so on and so on.
And now I come to conclusion, this is what
fascinates me, even the philosophical importance,
You know what Habermas abandons?
What the greatest first generation of Frankfurt School,
Adama and Horkheimer, called dialectic of enlightenment,
which means the horrors that were happening,
colonialism or Gulag, Shoah, they are not some remainder
of a dark medieval past, they are the results of
the imminent antagonisms of the project of European
modernity. With Khabramas, this disappears, just we
need more European enlightenment and so on and so on.
To conclude, then you can ask me questions if you want.
You know, we really live in sad times.
Not only is Germany, I can explain it more,
doing the most unethical thing you can imagine.
Everybody knows.
the logic is we did the holocaust so now as a dirty
deal with israel will say you were our victims
but in exchange we tolerate your crimes today
it's disgusting and just to conclude you know
people like to mention what happens today in haiti gangs taking over
but it's not just haiti even in the developed states everywhere.
Did you notice how the state power
cannot reproduce itself without direct use
of what are ultimately criminal gangs?
Trump here needs proud boys and so on.
And in Israel, let's face it, settler's movement of the West Bank
are illegal criminal gangs subtly used by Israeli establishment.
And this is where we are, unfortunately, where we are coming today.
To use the pathetic term, half a minute,
the masks are falling, literally.
I was shocked, you know, my reaction was like, you know,
in Tom and Jerry, when something happens, the eyes pop out,
and then my reaction when Netanyahu, a month ago or when,
said publicly, from the river to the sea, but the big Israel.
So what was still now done more discreetly is now done openly.
We are entering a new era, extremely dangerous
era, and I, in all my naivety, who still think
maybe there is something good, although they
are hypocritical in this European human rights,
I'm saying what is happening now in Gaza is the death of Europe.
In the sense of, you know, you talk to a Palestinian, he will tell
you, yes, European human rights are bumps which are falling on us.
And finally, Norman Finkelstein.
Thank you.
Is it working?
Yes.
Well, thank you for having me, and I want to
publicly thank Jenny Sternweiler and Holter
because both of them represent, for me at any rate, both of them at
their relatively young ages, and they represent the new generation.
For myself, I feel very hopeful that they
will carry on the tradition of trying to
fight back and trying to use your mind,
as well as your passion, in the struggle.
Muin is an old friend at this point, and a colleague and a comrade,
and we both together had our date with destiny, which will probably
be marked as a world historic event, and I'm glad it was with
Muin, although I still insist he was much too proper for my case.
There's obviously no silver lining in a genocide,
and it would be sinful to try to pretend there's one.
So, not casting it as a silver lining, I would rather simply cast
my remarks as why I believe, as
sparing it as the situation is, why
I believe what we're doing is useful and why we should not, for a
moment, relent in the face of
with clearly unsatisfactory results.
So I'm just going to review some items from the
past six months which have made me hopeful, even
though, as I say, for those who won't make it
to the finishing line, there is no consolation.
This will be a very personalized list.
As we will attest, very early on in the events
following October 7, there were some people who
were pressing to try to make this a genocide
case before the International Court of Justice,
and I found that wholly a waste of time.
I couldn't believe that any country on God's
earth would risk a confrontation with the United
States on behalf of an effectively stateless
people and a people without no power and no wealth.
So I was quite shocked when South Africa stepped
forward, and stepped forward not just as a token
gesture, but they stepped forward in a very
professional and one would have to say profound way.
They produced an application for the court, which
had literally applications like a brief for the
court, which had literally hundreds of footnotes
and was extremely polished in its presentation.
They chose very impressive people to represent South Africa, including my
old friend John Dugard, the international jurist, and a very impressive
fellow who even at 87 years old and he was wobbling a little as he came
up to the microphone, but he still
gave a very powerful presentation.
In many ways it was a beautiful delegation of men,
women, black, white, foreigners, South Africans.
It was, to the extent that it's possible, it sort of was anticipatory
of a better world and they were doing it all for the people of Gaza.
One of the things that struck me about the footnotes, and
here are notes that I found a little academic but will forgive
me, one of the things that struck me about the footnotes is
it depended entirely on UN agencies and UN documentation.
There are a few references to human rights groups, and
for anybody who has been involved in this matter for a
sustained period of time, you know that there are hundreds
and hundreds and hundreds of reports put out every year.
And you can't but roll your eyes and wonder,
isn't this all a waste of trees, this
accumulation of reports which really nobody
except maybe five people on God's earth read?
And suddenly all the labors of those people who week
after week after week chronicled the death, the hunger,
the destruction, and all those papers which were just
accumulating dust and cobwebs, they suddenly came to life.
It was for myself an awakening that sometimes
you're laboring away in a corner, think
it's all a waste of time, why am I doing this,
nobody's reading it, and suddenly it became
the raw material for an application to the
ICJ, which was because of the precision,
Because of the neutrality of the organizations,
it became irresistible and invincible.
And that brings me to the third point, what happened on the ICJ itself.
I spoke every day, either in email or a conversation with Maureen.
I kept doing the numbers.
There's no possibility they can get more than
six states on board for this plausible genocide.
I would name the states and, of course, I said, of course, forget
the United States, forget Germany, don't even waste your time.
I also said forget Australia.
I was happily wrong.
I'm glad I'm wrong for a good cause.
It was 15 to 2.
The only two dissents were the Israeli judge
and the court, and this woman from Uganda.
I hope she got a nice car and a ring for her,
which clearly she didn't even write what she wrote.
It was very obvious.
Then the ICJ was fifteen to two, but it didn't stop.
Africa went back a second time.
It produced a very professional statement again.
A lot of footnotes.
It went back a third time for the people of Gaza.
It wouldn't stop.
It wouldn't relent.
And then a new case was opened up before the
ICJ regarding a Kindred but separate matter.
So now there are two Israel cases in the ICJ.
And then lo and behold, guess what happens?
Nicaragua enters the picture and it files a case
against Germany for abandoning the genocide in Gaza.
You suddenly saw all these possibilities open up for initiatives.
They haven't resolved anything for
sure, but possibilities, potentialities.
I haven't yet read the German, the Nicaraguan
one, or the German response, but I have to
say I had a hearty laugh because I did listen
to one of the spokespersons for the Germans.
The Germans like to say, oh, we do it for states for its own
because we have a special who committed to Israel because of the
Holocaust, and the Nicaraguan, he steps up to the, who was a
farmer, who was the Nicaraguan representative to the Netherlands.
He says, well, you know what, the Germans
are making a lot of money off of this war,
and he starts going through all the military
contracts, and suddenly the mask is off a little.
all about states' raison, you know, serenity
terminology, and making a lot of bucks off of it.
I'm going to have to wrap up, I want to give credit to two groups of people.
First of all, I found the reaction of the young
people in the past six months to be absolutely
heroic and totally inspiring, the fact that they
keep coming out, coming out, and coming out.
I don't remember that from the War of Vietnam days.
We would have a mass demonstration maybe once every six
months or maybe more, maybe once every three months.
But the persistence, the tenacity of the
young people has been truly inspiring.
I know when I go to the demonstrations,
there's usually 40 years separating me
and the next oldest person in the crowd,
mostly 25-year-olds, I would guess.
And the last group of people I would want
to acknowledge are the hoofies. I find it
deeply inspiring that the poorest nation on
earth, as I understand it, is that correct?
In the Middle East because I read it the other day
on the planet, but no, it's in the Middle East.
Their tenacity, their willingness to suffer,
and it always brings to mind, and I'll end
on that note, for those of you who have read
Rousseau's Second Discourse, he makes the
argument that what he calls savage man is
much more moral than civilized man, because
he says the thing that humanizes people, who
makes people human, it's not their reason,
it's their capacity for pity, and that pity is a natural faculty and
pity is the source of everything that's positive in human beings.
And he says, the more educated you become,
first of all, the more egotistical you become,
and secondly, with your education you develop
the faculty to rationalize doing nothing.
So he says, a philosopher who looks out his window
and sees somebody being monged on his Outside
in the street the philosopher only has to close
his ears and say Perish if you will, I am safe
That's the philosophy of the philosopher's credo
But those who are not being quote-unquote civilized
They don't have the capacity to rationalize
their indifference to human suffering and
And, I've always found that to be a credible thesis, and
I think it's borne out by the actions of the Houthis.
Yesterday, Jamie, as it happens, he sent me a clip, which I
guess you saw, and it was some Yemeni fishermen, they were
anti-Houthi, and they were talking about how they're suffering
because the U.S. is here, Iran is there, and they can't fish.
But they said, and we can affirm it, they said,
we don't care, the people of Gaza are suffering.
The Houthis are their enemy.
They said, we don't care if it's for the
suffering people of Palestine, of Gaza.
We accept it.
It was a beautiful sentiment and an inspiring one for me.
Thank you.
Thank you all very much.
I want to start by asking each of you really, let's stick with you
Norman in the first instance because you talked about the hope that
the ICJ case, the one that South Africa brought gave you, and at the
time the US Secretary of State said that the case was without merit.
similar was said immediately after the case had been presented
and Israel had presented its defense and just a couple of days
ago in front of the Senate the US Secretary of Defense said
there was nothing to see here they had no evidence of a genocide.
Given that what the United States does and its very very slow shifting
position over the last six months what what do you make of what What
is possible for the United States in terms of saving face, a profound
change in U.S. foreign policy, it's changing attitude towards Israel.
How do you reflect on what they've been saying to date, very recently?
Well, I think the biggest change, it's not at the practical
political level, it's at the level of public opinion.
And I'll give you two examples to illustrate the point.
The first, almost breathtaking moment was when Charles
Schumer delivered his speech on the current situation.
Now Senator Schumer has been in the U.S. Senate
the foremost supporter of the State of Israel.
He opposed the Iran deal.
I think he and Menendez in New Jersey were the only two
senior senators, Democrat senators, to oppose the deal.
And he has an awful track record.
In 2010, he went before a group of Orthodox rabbis, and he said that we
should economically strangle Gaza, you know, Gaza with a million children.
He said we should economically strangle it.
He read his speech, it was quite remarkable.
First of all, he allocated exactly the same degree of responsibility for
the current impasse to Israel and to
Hamas, or Israel and the Palestinians.
He said on the one hand the problem is Netanyahu
and the Israeli far right, and then he said
on the other hand, the problem is Hamas and
the corruption of the Palestinian authority.
He was very careful to balance it.
And then he proceeded to try to defend the claim
that Israel is not a settler colonial state.
About six months ago that wasn't even a
subject of discussion among those elites.
But But suddenly he felt compelled to rationally
explain why he thought that's historically incorrect.
And then he proceeded to have to explain
why the idea of one state was wrong.
One state is officially by the IHRA – International House
and Residence Association – definition of antisemitism.
One state is officially anti-Semitic.
What did Schumer do?
Senator Schumer began by saying, I know many
idealistic young people support one state.
He didn't say they're all anti-Semites.
He said they're idealistic young people.
And so now you saw the Democratic Party has to contend
with a new reality at the base of that party, namely
there is something fundamentally illegitimate about
Israel, either historically or as a Jewish state.
And that to me is in a very short period of time,
though you could say it was percolating for a long time.
That's a historical shift in public opinion.
One last thing and I'll make it very big.
I opened up the New York Times yesterday.
They have this article about how Iran is supplying all
these weapons to the West Bank and a giant yuan from there.
So I was just curious.
I turned According to the letter's comment section,
I sent it to Moin, and he again can affirm,
you know what the letter's read like?
Why shouldn't Iran supply weapons to the West Bank?
They're going to occupy people, they have the right
to arm resistance, and who the hell is the United
States talking about other countries supplying
weapons to people in the vote? I was totally shy.
This is the New York Times, usually letters
like that would just go right for the discard.
And suddenly there was one, am I
correct, one after another after another.
So even the Times readers have fallen out of
the range of legitimate opinion on this time.
I wonder if we can bring you in here on this whole issue of
the two-state solution versus the one-state solution because
for so long the two-state solution has been the mantra and
increasingly people are talking about it as being a hollow mantra
and of course there are huge problems from all
sorts of sides if we talk about one-state solution
because it then means that it's no longer an
ethno-nationalist project, it's no longer a Jewish state.
I wonder how you would reflect on the
shift inside the Middle East on that issue.
Yes, well, I would have three comments.
I think the first one to make is that when Western
politicians talk about a two-state settlement,
We need to look at their actions and not their words, and
for them, two-state settlement is a diversionary charade.
It's smoke and mirrors.
It's to use words to deflect attention from
their actions, because their actions are
undermining any settlement, and most particularly
the prospect of an end to Israeli occupation,
because that's being entrenched with the act of
support and or passive act. essence of Western states.
The second question becomes whether a two-state settlement
remains practical or is it practical, is it feasible?
And I've written about this and I think that as a
practical matter, a two-state settlement remains feasible.
An Israeli withdrawal to the 1967 boundaries.
And the The dismantling of the settlements and a just
resolution to the refugee question, as a matter of principle,
remains practical and I think a useful way to look at
this is to compare Israel's position in the West Bank with
Britain's position in Ireland in 1915, France's position in
Algeria in 1950, Ethiopia's position in Tigray, sorry, in
Eritrea in 1985, Indonesia's position in East Timor in
1990, and I think in all of those cases you find, excuse me,
a foreign presence that was in many respects more entrenched
than is the Israeli presence in the occupied territories.
Now, the third point becomes, OK, well, if it is indeed
practical, what has happened in the past six months?
And here I would argue that for many
people who previously consider this
practical, who also consider it no
longer desirable, the question becomes,
can you have lasting, durable peace in the Middle East with the
continued existence of a irrational, genocidal, apartheid regime?
Or does this regime and its key institutions need to be
dismantled as a precondition for peace in the Middle East?
And I think these are questions that are increasingly
being raised that are open for discussion.
I don't think there are easy answers in this respect.
And my last comment also is that I do not in any way base
my analysis on the so-called failure of the Oslo process.
I think Oslo has been one of the most successful diplomatic processes
since 1945 for the simple reason that it was never about ending occupation.
It was never about a two-state settlement.
It was never about establishing an independent
Palestinian state, it was about reformulating and
consolidating permanent Israeli control over the
Palestinians, and to that extent it's been a success.
Coleman, do you want to come back and respond to that?
My own view is that now is simply not
the time to be talking about solutions.
First of all, there's no representative
Palestinian organization to negotiate with.
And the Israeli political spectrum is—
and I don't use the term loosely, I've not
used it before, but I don't use it loosely—the
Israeli political spectrum is insane.
It goes from the right to the far right to the ultra-right.
There's no center and there's no left, that's just a factual matter.
So there's nothing to negotiate with.
You could say around 2000 with the Camp David
Accord, with the Oslo and the Camp David,
you could say in those years, and you look closely at the
negotiations that I have, they were arguing about percentages.
So Ehul Barak says we want to keep 80%
of the settlers, the illegal settlers,
we want to keep them in any final settlement, we want to keep 80 percent.
Elmer says we want to keep 87 percent.
The Palestinians say you can keep 60 percent.
Israelis say we want to keep about 10 percent of the West Bank.
The Palestinians say, we'll let you keep 2% of the West Bank.
Now, I'm not saying they were close.
There was still a gap, maybe not a chasm, but there was a significant gap.
But we were talking about percentages.
Now the current government of Israel, we can't extract from
them a broom closet or a bread box for the Palestinians.
So there's no place for discussion at this point.
There are no two sites where any kind of argument can even be made.
Just the second thing, we have to be realistic, in my opinion.
We still may be very—wars can last a long time.
The Ukraine war is over two years now, and then you can
look at the Vietnam War or you can look at World War II.
After about six months, I don't like to say it, but I think there's a
very good chance we're still closer to the beginning than to the end.
Because if you read the Israeli statements
and you read the analyses, like I read
one last night from JINSA, one of these
Jewish neoconservative lunatic organizations,
and They say no end is possible unless
there is an absolute, total, unequivocal
defeat inflicted on Hamas and an absolute,
total, unequivocal victory for Israel.
And on the other side, groups like Hezbollah
are saying we will not accept a total,
unequivocal defeat by Hamas, that we
will do what's necessary to prevent that.
And so I believe we still might be quite far from the end of this current
situation, and It's just pointless now to be talking about solutions.
Slava, let's talk about the kind of moral reckoning that needs to take place.
Even if we were to accept what Norman is saying,
that this could go on for a lot, lot longer,
the fact that it has got as far as it has now,
with 33,000 people being killed in six months,
which might have seemed unthinkable when you compare it, say, to 2021,
when, you know, Korta, help me with the
numbers, how many people were killed in 2021?
So it was 1,600 or something like that.
The biggest ones Operation Cast Lead was 1,200 people, 1,400 people.
Operation Protective Edge was 2,200 people killed,
so we're just, you know, completely different.
So given that the Western world, which continues to regard itself,
even though that kind of idea is falling
apart before our very eyes, still continues
to regard itself as the kind of moral
arbiter of what happens in the world.
What are we to make of the need for a moral reckoning of the failure to
have protected the thousands and thousands of innocent people in Gaza?
Crucial question, I would like just to make
some brief remarks so that I don't get lost.
First, that problem about 30,000 dead and so on,
I think it's not just a question of data.
Even the Western media don't deny this data.
But there is, especially in Germany, but also in
other states, there is one mode of interpreting it,
and in Germany, it's legalized.
Even the relatively moderate minister of culture,
I would call her minister of barbarism Claudia Roach, she explicitly
said, she said, you can literally, again, I had a Tom and Jerry reaction,
she said, yes, we can talk about Palestinian suffering, but we should
make it clear that ultimately Hamas which is responsible for it.
So it's as if, you know, Hamas is engaged in a big suicidal operation and
Israel just somehow got God into it, you know, this has to be changed.
And also, to change, as it was pointed out, this public perception is crucial.
For example, we should insist how Israel – okay, we hear from
Habermas and so on, the only democratic state – I'm sorry, but a
month ago or when Netanyahu justified the opposition against a
two-state solution which meant big Israel from the river to the sea.
He said it's the only democratic solution
because, I don't know if this is true, but he
wrote some statistic that now almost 90, 90
percent of Jews there in Israel are against it.
I'm sorry, but if you take into account all the
area controlled by Israel, it's almost 50-50.
There are just a little bit more maybe Jews than Palestinians.
She even didn't mention, you see, this is apartheid in practice.
So what can we do?
And another thing, maybe along the practical
lines that you normally emphasize public opinion,
Something will happen like I know.
Maybe I have a little bit to push into their
asses with some of my influence in Slovenia,
but I learned from reliable sources that now,
till the end of June, July, Spain, Ireland,
and this is very nice here, my small influence comes Slovenia and, okay,
it's not the greatest say in the world, will publicly recognize Palestine.
And these small signs that you normally mention
didn't even a guy whom I would not trust my mother to his house.
David Cameron, at some point, mentioned maybe we should.
Foreign Secretary of the United Kingdom.
Yeah, yeah.
And yeah, yeah.
And you know what's now this political
situation in the United Kingdom, though?
You had one big, big central right-wing party.
It's called a Labour Party.
Then you have some more crazy right-wing party.
Okay, but what's about, sorry, let me go on.
So what I want to say is that now we have
to make, as you pointed out, the next step.
Now it's legitimized to talk about Palestinian suffering.
And now we go to the next stage
Well, what does this suffering mean?
The logic if, yes, you have to sympathize, you break, you put those
stupid, how do you call it, parachutes with, but what does this mean?
I think there is one, there is one thought of
it for me is the best symbol of the situation.
I found it in big media.
It's the same photo you see from Gaza, you see in front Israeli bombs,
bombs made by USA, falling on Gaza, destroying buildings,
and just behind, parachutes with food falling down.
That's the catch.
So let me just very briefly to conclude with one remark.
You know where we have to work.
How these prohibitions, what, where is it permitted to say?
When I said what I said in Frankfurt,
The most disgusting thing for me is that literally dozens of
people, hardline Germans, came to me privately, literally looked
around carefully and then whispered to me, you know, basically
I agree with you, it's just not the right moment to say it.
My answer was, of course, I know what you mean.
The right moment will be to say it when it will mean nothing to say it.
Now it means something to say this.
So you know what, really, I wonder if I address
this also to you so that finally would agree.
I don't trust them.
But for example, you probably all
know who me, if you are intelligent, but
also the ex-bosses of Sinbad Moser,
but a guy called, I think, Ami Ayadon.
Okay.
He's now retired.
Once you are retired, you can say many things,
but nonetheless, he wrote a comment or interview
where he said the only solution is allow
political subjectivity to Palestinians
and even a very practical proposal, set free Marvin Barghouti and so on.
Where are we when, if you say in
Germany, what, an ex-cap or a chief
of Shin Bet I think, you are almost arrested if you say this in German.
So it's not just, you know, one thing is to
say things in places like this one and so on.
At this point, the struggle is effective and it's not a
lost struggle to gradually change the public perception.
I want to just pick up on, you didn't answer
the question about the moral recipe for you.
I never answered the question.
Well, I'll move on then.
I wonder if you will just say a little about how you account for
the fact that in your essay you chronicle and document so carefully
every single instance of Hamas being willing to engage and willing to
indicate its efforts to be moderate or to engage in a peace process
And yet the narrative that most people, the majority
of people who are looking at what is happening,
the narrative that they absorb is the exact opposite as
framed by Western governments and Israel in particular.
How do you account for that, that lack of knowledge
of the very detailed chronicle that you set out?
Noam Chomsky wrote a book about it, Manufacturing Consent.
The fact that the Western media in general is
beholden to the interests of mega corporations,
has a vested interest in repeating the dogmas of the American
state, and for that reason are
uninterested in telling Americans
and Westerners more broadly the truth about what Israel has done
to Gaza, not just since October 7th, but repeatedly before that.
I can give one example, Operation Cast Lead.
The media narrative about Operation Cast Lead was generally
one that depicted Israel responding to Hamas rocket fire
in an act of self-defense, but in fact Operation Cast Lead
was the product of an Israeli violation of a ceasefire.
Ceasefire had been signed in June of 2008, and Israeli officials readily
admitted that the Hamas militants carefully adhered to that ceasefire and
that it brought, I'm quoting an Israeli defense official now, brought a
large measure of peace and quiet to the
Israeli communities surrounding Gaza.
The deal in that ceasefire was meant to
be that Hamas would cease firing rockets,
which it did, and Israel was going to lift its illegal and crushing blockade.
It did not.
It barely eased it.
And on November 4th, as Norman's documented
this in the most detail, but on November 4th,
while Americans were transfixed by their presidential election,
Israel conducts a raid into Gaza, kills six Palestinian militants.
And at that point, the rockets begin to fly and Israel begins bombing Gaza.
On December 19th, the ceasefire, it was a six
month ceasefire agreement, the ceasefire expires.
And within days Hamas offers, both through
somebody associated with the Carter Center as
well as European governments like Norway and
through the United Nations, offers Israel
a return to that same ceasefire, the one the Palestinians
were upholding and that Israel incessantly violated.
Two days later, on December 21st, the Israeli
cabinet met and decided it was going to bomb
Gaza and launch a major operation there.
In fact, they've been planning it for years, ever since 2006.
They were humiliated by Hezbollah in Lebanon.
But not only do they decide that they're
going to start bombing Gaza at that December
21st cabinet meeting, they also decide to lie about when they're going to begin bombing.
Tippi Livni meets with the Egyptian president
at the time, Mubarak, and lets him know that
it will not be until the Sunday, December 28th, that Israel will make a
decision about what it's going to do about the escalating situation in Gaza.
On December 27th, at 1130 a.m.
in the morning, Israel drops 100 tons of bombs on little Gaza.
It kills, according to human rights organizations,
up to 300 Palestinians in the space of minutes.
If October 7th, yes, was the bloodiest day in
the history of the Israel-Palestine conflict,
certainly the beginning of Operation
Cast Lead were the bloodiest few minutes.
Ehud Barak, the former Israeli prime minister at the time, the
defense minister, boasted that he had killed 350 terrorists
within the space of a few minutes at the opening of Cast Lead.
And of course, Israel then went on to carry
out what Amnesty International called 22 days
of death and destruction in Gaza, killing some
1,400 Palestinians, probably 80% of them civilians.
So when you hear talk, for example,
about October 7th, people saying that Hamas must be destroyed
because it violated a ceasefire and committed this horrible atrocity.
I don't see any reason why that same argument
couldn't be applied to Israel and what it
did at the beginning of Cast Lead, and not
just Cast Lead, but again in 2012, Operation
pillar of defense, and then Operation – sorry, in 2014 once more.
I want to just pick up on a few of the
threads of comments that we've heard so far.
Really just to try and examine – and I won't bring you in, Muin,
here – the relationship between governments and the people.
So in the Middle East, it seems to me that
whatever machinations go on with autocratic
States in the Gulf and, you know, absolute
monarchies and so on, the relationship between
those states and governments and the West is
so far removed from the Arab in the street
and not the Arab in the street and the need
for those governments and states to get the
balance right between what Arabs feel about
Palestinians and Palestine and what might
suit those in power yes and I mean we're
often told we're often told thank you
we're often told there is no democracy in the Arab world because of some
backward culture, backward religion, backwardness, and sideways that.
Well, let's take an example.
Palestinians, you don't even need to go to the Arab world.
You have a Palestinian authority which is propped up and supported by the
West in an inverse relationship to its legitimacy among its own people.
It seems the more credibility and legitimacy
loses among its own people, the greater the
support it gets from Western... it's literally
being propped up by Israel and the West.
Of course, you know, those aren't the only reasons for the absence of
democracy in the Arab world, but they are absolutely central to any analysis.
And to say, oh, Arabs just want to blame the West for their own ills.
Again, look at the Palestinian example.
In 2006, the Palestinians held an election
that was certified by the Carter Center as, I believe,
not only entirely free and fair, but I think as the most free
and fair of all elections that the Carter Center had monitored.
Well, whatever one may think of Hamas, Hamas
won that fair and square, and the Western
reaction was to put in place a process of
blockade, of demonization, of delegitimization,
of repeated military onslaughts on the Gaza
Strip that led precisely to the genocidal
Assault on the Palestinians of the
Gaza Strip that we are experiencing today
So don't come to me with stories about the
West is looking for a democratic partner
Whenever there's been an inkling of a democratic partner.
He's been eliminated.
I Just want to read from from Coulter's essay where he
quotes on the Hillary Clinton when she was a senator
If we were going to push for an election and we should
have made sure to determine who was going to win.
Precise six.
I wanted to just take up where Walter and Mooin left off.
In my opinion, and obviously we can disagree on it,
that when you pass moral judgments on other people's actions,
In my opinion, you have to also examine what were the options
available in the context of the decisions that were made.
Now, as Muin pointed out, a brutal blockade was imposed on Gaza.
It really began around 1991, it was called
a closure, and then it was ratcheted up with
the election in 2006 when Hamas won,
and then was ratcheted up again in 2007.
And at that point a process began which, because of the brutality of the
blockade, turned Gaza into what the economists called a human rubbish heap.
Now, it was Gaza, 2 million people, 70% of
them refugees from 1948 and their descendants,
half of them children, a million, more than
a million children, and they had been reduced
as a consequence of that blockade into, to
repeat the expression, a human rubbish heap.
That's the context, as you might call it, the socio-economic context.
And nobody can go in and nobody can come out.
Most of the young people who burst the gates
of Gaza on October 7th were born into that
rubbish heap, were living in that rubbish
heap, and as things looked on October 6th,
They were going to die in that rubbish.
That's the socioeconomic context.
Now Coulter fills in the political context.
In that period, on numerous occasions, Hamas
attempted a diplomatic resolution of the conflict.
Were their proposals perfect?
No.
Would they have required a lot of intense
negotiation to achieve a settlement?
In my opinion, yes, but there were certainly reasonable proposals
and they were a basis to try to solve the conflict diplomatically.
All of those diplomatic proposals were perectorally
dismissed and they weren't even acknowledged as proposals.
So now, what options are left for the Palestinians?
There was an option, which I embarrassingly have to acknowledge,
I was the one promoting in all of my talks for several years.
I thought the possibility, the option of nonviolent civil resistance could work.
And on March 30, 2018, it was a popular initiative, it
did not start with Hamas, it was a popular Initiative,
they tried the Nonviolent Civil Resistance March of
Return, what was called, yes, the Great March of Return.
And as there was a very good UN report,
it runs to 250 single-spaced pages.
It's a very exhaustive, even by the UN
standards, it was a remarkably exhaustive,
wasn't as large as the Goldstone Report, but it was a very significant report.
And it was a remarkably detailed report.
A large chunk of that report is given over to describing what
happened to those marchers in the Great March of Returns.
Just to give the salient facts, number one, they
describe the march as beginning as people will remember.
It began as a festive occasion.
There was singing, there was dancing, there were circus-like performances.
People were very enthusiastic about this prospect possibility and potentiality.
What did Israel do?
It lined up its best snipers,
It's the best snipers along the perimeter with Gaza.
And then the report with a lot of detail,
it goes through what those snipers did.
They quote the Israeli government as saying,
every bullet landed where it was intended to land.
There's no question here of like WCK mistakes, errors.
Every bullet landed where it was intended to land, okay?
So the report says Israel targeted the snipers
methodically, systematically, premeditatedly,
it targeted children, it targeted medics,
it targeted journalists, and it targeted
disabled people, it targeted double
amputees, it targeted people in wheelchairs.
He targeted people on crutches who were
300 meters away from the perimeter fence.
Now anybody who understands anything about non-violence knows as a
method of struggle, it can only work if it evokes or elicits our reaction
from bystanders, from non-participants,
either as perpetrators or victims.
The whole point of Martin Luther King's nonviolent
campaign was, he said that we can evoke sympathy,
action from the federal government, from the North, if
we exhibit the violence that's entrenched in this system.
The only way you can exhibit the violence entrenched
in this system is you have to go out and demonstrate.
They will come out with their dogs, they will come out with their fire hoses,
sometimes they will come out with their
guns, and then people are supposed to react.
If our federal government did not react, if the
North did not react, then everybody would just die.
non-violence is a dead end.
And the fact that as Israel targeted children,
medics, journalists, disabled people, nobody reacted.
I have to acknowledge not even the Palestine Solidarity Movement reacted.
So I have to embarrassingly say I was shamefaced after that
because I had been in touch with some people in in some positions.
I was the one that was counseling it,
and it was a complete and total failure.
And so I say, we come to October 6th, the night.
Diplomacy, it doesn't work.
Nonviolent civil resistance, it doesn't work.
I'm willing to accept what Muin says because
he's much more knowledgeable than me.
He said the Saudi deal was not really going to happen, but I'm
sure Moin will agree with me, many people thought it would happen.
And so they thought this whole Arab-Israeli
conflict was going to be solved above the
heads of the people of Gaza.
That it would be happily ever after between
the Gulf states, Saudi, Israel, the United
States and the people of Gaza, they were going
to languish and die in that concentration camp.
That was their fate and their future.
And unless somebody can present to me what options did
they not exploit, what choices did they have at that point.
I for one, recognizing that atrocities of a
significant magnitude occurred on October 7th,
I for one find it very difficult to condemn what happened
on October 7th even as I recognize atrocities occur.
Okay, a moment then just to,
because we've got about 20 minutes, I think, to open it up to
the floor and I'll give you the chance, Slavoj, to respond.
I can't really see the lights on us,
but yes, I can, if you put hands up, that would be great.
Yes, no, you're so shy.
Is that one right back here?
Can you stand up?
Sure.
Sorry, is there somebody?
Yeah, please stand up.
Is there a microphone?
Do you have a microphone?
Does it matter?
I think if you talk about it.
Hi, thank you.
I want to go back to the question of the politics in Israel.
So you talked about there's the right, the center right, the far right.
I mean, we are also seeing this sort of
protest movement growing against Netanyahu
to get the hostages home that is not
talking a whole lot about the Palestinians.
And you know, I think at all.
If at all, right.
And I guess my question is, if we assume that the global movement
in support of Palestine continues to grow, and the movement
inside of Israel, maybe it grows in its way, but in a way that
is really to sort of calcify a less far-right version of Israel.
What do you do about that?
What do you do about this population of, seven million people in Israel,
who seem to just be refused to accept
that there was something fundamentally
oppressive and wrong about their society?
Is that directed at anyone in particular?
I mean, I was thinking, Norman, I'd love
to hear your thoughts and whoever else.
Of course.
I'd rather hear from moving first.
Well, I think the problem with this society
is you can think of it as a spoiled child that runs them up in a porcelain store.
And the store owner, instead of demanding
that the parents pay the price of the broken
porcelain starts telling the parents what a cute
kid it is and can you please break some more.
I think Israeli society at one level we need to show a bit of understanding.
If you've been allowed to get away with
everything for so long and if total impunity
is the default setting, you can't really expect this society to act differently.
People talk about how small the peace movement in
Israel was, and it isn't infinitesimally small,
but in a sense it's a miracle there's one at all,
given the nature of this society in relation to its
Western sponsors and the absolute
impunity it enjoys for anything and
everything it does towards the Palestinian people, including genocide.
Even that is being actively supported by the West.
So in terms of these protests you're talking
about, you know, you had a very large
protest movement before October 7th against
the Netanyahu government's legislative agenda.
The judicial reforms?
Yes, the so-called judicial reforms.
The leaders of that process movement
were actively keeping any discussion of
Israeli-Palestinian relations, to use that
euphemism, out of the protest movement.
And now, it's simply about protesting against the government
to cut a deal with Hamas so that the captives are released.
But other than that, to the best of my understanding,
it really doesn't have a political agenda
in terms of changing the nature of Israeli-Palestinian relations.
So if you want to change Israeli society, don't look at Israel.
Look at those who are enabling Israel.
And those who have taught Israeli society that
anything goes up to and including genocide,
that there will never be accountability, that impunity is a
default, so that's really what the fundamental problem is.
Isn't there also an issue with what you were
talking about earlier Norman, the Chuck Schumer
comments, this perception that seems to be
prevailing, that if Netanyahu was the person
that was gotten rid of, then things would be better,
without taking into account the kind of entrenched structural views
and consciousness and psychology that prevails in Israel.
There are a number of comments to make.
First of all, I totally agree with you, it's not
Netanyahu's war any more than it's Putin's war.
It's a consensus across the elites in the
case of both, and it's not just Netanyahu.
In the case of Israel, I'll speak reluctantly about
Russia because I don't know the popular sentiment.
In the case of Russia, it's the whole of, excuse
me, the case of Israel is the entire society.
If you look at the polling data, roughly 90
percent of Israelis believe, or 88 percent
believe that Israel is using enough force or insufficient
force, about 40 percent believe Israel is using
insufficient force in Gaza, there's about 12 percent
who have second thoughts about what Israel is doing.
So I don't think, I agree with you, I don't
think it's correct to describe it as say
Netanyahu's war and I don't think Senator
Schumer was accurate as if to say there were
an election, somebody better, maybe a Gantz,
who campaigned when he ran for office.
He campaigned on the destruction he wreaked on Gaza in 2014.
That was his campaign video.
So I can't say I'm optimistic on that score,
that it's just Netanyahu and a handful of others.
I would say, and I don't say this happily, I think it's pointless to try to change
the attitudes of Israelis now, just as it was
pointless during the civil rights movement
to try to change the attitudes of whites in the South.
It required external force up to and including the
introduction of federal troops to desegregate the South.
There were a handful of people in the South, whites,
who had second thoughts about what was going on.
honestly opposed to it, but it was a tiny handful.
I don't believe you can expect, for all the
reasons that Maureen described, he left out
the ideological aspects of it, a very lethal
combination of notions of Jewish inferiority
and our inferiority—actually, our animality,
not inferiority—and there are all these
different levels of ideological, what's just called, ugliness,
that make it very hard to transform as early as it's decided.
I'll have to say, because I want to be fair
about these things, you could say the two,
In the very ugly history of the 20th century, you could
say the two most racist and imperialist countries in God's
earth were Germany and
Japan in the 1930s, and the kinds of crimes
they committed during World War II were just total abominations.
We all know about the Germans once when the
Japanese killed about 26 million Chinese.
It was a very ugly, ugly war by the Japanese in Asia.
But countries changed, Germany did change, Japan did change.
So I don't believe in these notions of original sin.
But I do agree, I've come to agree with Maureen, that
a serious revamping of Israeli society is necessary.
How that occurs, how it unfolds, I can't say.
But it's just really, it's such an ugly
place now, and has been for a very long time.
And I'll admit to something, you know, when
I'm reading the coverage now, the coverage
now, now, against Israel, it's really horrible.
The positions, it's put itself.
The position it's put itself, that being by nature I always support the
underdog, I almost feel sorry for what it did to itself, because it's horrible.
And these folks, they don't even see it, what they've done.
It's like a statement to an abortion.
And maybe the whole idea was wrong from the
beginning and maybe it was wrong at the beginning
But, there was a lot of things wrong with America at the beginning.
The U.S. figured out a way, not to make it a great
place, and it did require the extermination of the native
population, you can't forget that, but the U.S. seemed
to have some capacity, some capacity for self-reform.
And I don't know what Israel does.
Let's take some more questions.
I'm sure.
There's a hand stuck there at the back.
Yeah, I actually just want to follow up on that.
I mean, so like, Ilan Pompeii talks about the
Israel of Tel Aviv and Israel of the Central.
I mean, Israel is a very unified
society when it comes to Palestine,
but it is internally an extremely polarized society.
Israelis perceive themselves as living in a highly polarized society.
And I think one of the things if you know
Israelis, and you know Israelis that are in
Israel of Tel Aviv, that you'll hear since
October 7, particularly, but really 2023,
I mean, there was this idea in the Israel of Tel Aviv that, you know, we
can sort of of marginal, like we don't have to resolve the question of
Palestine and we can just sort of continue living in what feels like a
normal society where we can go to cafes in Tel Aviv and eat croissants.
And 2023, first with the crisis, as they call it,
the crisis of democracy, and then with October 7th,
there's a massive, across the Israel of Tel Aviv,
disinvestment in the in the future of living in Israel.
So many people all of a sudden talking about there's no future here, we're
we're gonna live under constant threat of violence from Hamas, from Tikalah,
from Iran, and these were the people that were sort of the ambassadors to
the worlds of the sort of and humane, liberal, enlightened Israel, right?
I mean, these were the sort of educated
professionals and intellectuals who went to
their conferences and presented themselves
as living in a normal nation among nations.
And there's a massive sort of movement among those
people of disinvestment in the national project.
And many people who just talk about leaving, actually get a lot
of people who talk about moving back to Europe well it started
to happen as well it was there a specific question I mean the
comments are really really interesting yeah yeah so the question
is just do you perceive that as a major factor because I know
people say I mean Israeli society is beyond reform when it comes
to the question of the Palestinians but do you You perceive that
as a significant moving part in, yeah, events going forward.
Sir, do you want to take that one?
No, I want to go into a different direction.
Okay.
Can I just answer very briefly?
Go ahead, please.
Which is to say that I won't pretend to know more about this issue
than you do, and assuming that your observations are correct,
I think that makes the problem even more complicated
than was made out to be, because that would be the capacity for self-reform.
Simply doesn't exist.
I see other hands going off.
Just a question to anyone in the panel.
How likely do you think that this conflict will spread
in the region that other actors might get involved?
And does Israel have an interest in bringing, in enlarging this conflict?
Muhyin, you've referred to that in your MC.
Can you repeat the question?
Yeah, of course.
Is it in Israel's interest to escalate the war regionally?
And how likely is it that that might happen?
I think Israel would like to escalate conflict regionally because
it sees an opportunity to draw the U.S. directly into its conflict
with its adversaries and in an ideal situation, from Israel's
perspective, to provoke a direct Iranian-American confrontation.
Just very briefly, you're familiar with the recent Iranian attack on the
– sorry, the since Israeli attack on the Iranian consulate in Damascus.
And apparently, the Iranians have sent messages to
the Americans that if the Americans successfully
produce a permanent ceasefire, in other words,
an end to Israel's war in the Gaza Strip,
then as far as the Iranians are concerned, the file is closed.
And if the Americans fail, then the Iranians have decided
that in order to deter Israel, they will launch an
attack directly on Israeli territory, not through one of
their allied militias, but directly from Iran territory.
So in other words, if the Americans make
the choice not to end the war, together
would be a policy decision, and the
Iranians follow through on the threat,
that we could be looking at a very major
I just want to reiterate what I said earlier.
If the U.S. imposes a permanent ceasefire
as the quid pro quo for Iran not taking
any retaliatory action, the problem is
then Hamas will be able to declare victory.
And Israel will not accept that.
Israel is determined to get that absolute, unequivocal,
total victory and inflict the total defeat on Hamas.
And there's the second problem.
Right now, about 100,000 people are displaced
from northern Israel because of Hezbollah.
And Israel is not pleased about that fact either.
Will it give Hezbollah a pass?
I think personally, but we can disagree, he knows
better than me, personally, I don't believe it.
And then there's one third problem, the problem that Coulter
alluded to, it's very easy to break a permanent ceasefire.
You can agree to a permanent ceasefire, Israel can agree
to it, as they did, as Coulter pointed out in June 2008.
And then when Israel wanted a war, just provoked,
provoked, provoked, then there's the war
and And everybody forgets who provoked and, as
Milken claimed, it's acting itself a defence.
So personally, I don't attach any
significance or value to any declared
permanent ceasefire because looking at
the history, it's just very easy to break.
Can I just ask Colter a question about, just
picking up from Norman's point, on the declaration
that israel makes time and again to eliminate
hamas once and for all the the feasibility
of that because you do refer to that in your
essay the the fact that hamas is is many things
the social movement it's a militia there's this
political movement and it's also just an idea
yeah um the short answer is it's completely
impossible for israel to eliminate hamas even if
we were to accept, which I don't, that eliminating Hamas is a
morally unobjectionable, practically it's not going to happen.
Hamas is not just based in the Gaza Strip, it is based all
throughout the occupied territories and outside of them.
And furthermore, even if you can destroy
Hamas's military capabilities.
Israel claims that it has more or less wiped out Hamas's
military capabilities in the northern part of the Gaza Strip,
even if it does invade Rafah and, you know, comes back
with the severed heads of Sinwar and other Hamas leaders.
What it will not have done is done anything about the
source of Palestinian grievance, which we've
been talking about, which is so obvious.
Decades now of occupation, of apartheid, massacre, even if what arises
out of those ashes doesn't call
itself Hamas, it'll be the same problem.
I think we're gonna have to wrap up unless
somebody's got an urgent pressing question that
they, there's a hand going up here, I really
can't see all the way at the back of the room.
Why don't you take this one here.
I have a question.
Okay.
I was
I was wondering, in your opinion, why did Nicaragua
bring a case against Germany and not against the
USA, who seems to be the prime supporter of Israel,
either with weapons than with financial support?
I think because Nicaragua is in Central America and Germany is in Europe.
I want to go right to the back of the room.
Is there a hand that's gone up?
Not the person who asked about the Tel Aviv
question, because you've already had a question.
Sorry, sir.
In the front, here.
For any of you, is there any chance of
that relationship of total impunity,
of total toleration and support between the United States and Israel.
I mean, public opinion has changed significantly.
Is there any chance of that shifting
in any way, even small, in the future?
Who wants to say that?
Well, I think the changes that Norman and others have been talking about
of profound importance and lonely of profound political importance.
But it's going to take time for them to have an
impact on the types of questions that you're asking.
My response to that question, if you're asking about
it in the short term, is Biden, Blinken, Netanyahu,
of them, they're not going to be held accountable.
They're going to get away with their crimes.
That's the way the world unfortunately works.
But having said that, Lincoln's grandchildren,
whenever they want to study the Gaza genocide,
the 21st century, they will know that any
study of that genocide that doesn't assign a starring
role to their grandfather is an an incomplete account.
And unfortunately, I think that's probably the extent of accountability.
Karim Khan is still decorating his Christmas tree.
ICC is not gonna get involved.
The ICJ can take clear decisions,
but they can't be enforced.
The way the international system is currently structured,
there's unfortunately no accountability or
criminals in the sense that you're asking.
What a grim note on which to end,
but we are gonna have to draw it to a close.
Buy the book and keep talking.
Thank you very much indeed for coming.
Thank you.
And I didn't say thank you to the panel.
That was so rude of me.
Norman Finkelstein, Moon Ravani, Slavoj Zizek,
and Korta Lewis.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
我们都可以安静下来
活动就要开始了.
我叫奥利维亚.
我在 Or Books 工作 负责活动和宣传
我们很高兴今天能邀请到
我们出色的小组成员 作家 记者
活动家 哲学家 来参加我们的
"C大道现场 "系列活动之一
今晚 我们的活动是为了纪念这本精彩的书的发行
这本书在酒吧门口出售
穆因和库尔特都是这本书的撰稿人
不幸的是 编辑杰米
今晚无法前来 但我们出色的主持人拉齐娅
将由他致开幕词
我们希望您能参加我们更多的精彩活动
下一次活动将于 5 月 15 日举行
我们的另一本书《公司政变》
但现在 我将让位
非常感谢我们的小组成员和主持人
以及今晚到场的各位
非常感谢
谢谢大家
谢谢
谢谢 奥利维亚
谢谢 科林
非常感谢各位的到来
也感谢所有线上参加的朋友
请您暂时想象一下 我是这本书的编辑
杰米·斯特恩-维纳
这是他的开场白
他很抱歉不能来这里
因此 我首先要感谢全书出版社的奥利维亚
组织了这次会议
感谢拉齐娅为我主持会议
感谢所有小组成员的参与
就新书发布而言 这是一个阴郁的事件
但这又是一本阴郁的书和一个阴郁的时刻
根据最新的人道主义报告 以色列在加沙杀害了
33 000 多人 其中大部分是妇女和儿童
以色列还部分或完全摧毁了加沙 60% 以上的房屋
一场蓄意制造的饥荒即使还没有开始
也是迫在眉睫
10 月 联合国秘书长安东尼奥-古特雷斯注意到
这场灾难 引用 并非凭空发生的
本周 英勇的联合国巴勒斯坦难民救济和工程处指出
目前在那里发生的危机是前所未有的
这两种说法都是正确的
加沙所发生的一切是长期
多层次不公正的产物
也就是说 几十年来的额剥夺
吞并 围困和屠杀
目前的灾难在关键方面
也有新的突破
通过这本书 我试图阐明
加沙正在发生的事情
的连续性和分裂性
为读者提供必要的重要背景资料
让他们了解事情是如何发展到
今天这个可怕的地步的
同时也对冲突历史上的
一个转折点进行初步分析
科尔特·刘易斯根据自己的博士论文在书中所写的一章
贯穿了1967年以来巴以冲突的整个外交背景
他权威地指出
以色列曾有一次又一次的机会以合理的条件解决冲突
先是与巴勒斯坦解放组织
然后是在2006年当选后与数百个国家
我认为 正是因为以色列及其国际帮凶拒绝了这些机会
才导致了今天的局面
穆欣-拉巴尼的文章将加沙战争
置于两个关键的地区动态之中
一方面 美国促成和鼓励了
以色列与海湾国家之间的关系升温；
另一方面 哈马斯与由伊朗和真主党领导的
所谓“抵抗轴心”的关系则呈现出对比
书中最令人心碎的段落之一是
穆欣对倒霉的美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯的描述
他卑躬屈膝地穿梭于阿拉伯各国政府之间
乞求他们帮助以色列摆脱困境 结果除了那破碎的
死气沉沉的凝视之外 什么也没带回来
诺曼-芬克尔斯坦和斯拉沃伊-齐泽克
当然不需要我介绍
我只是借此机会感谢他们的参与
并特别感谢诺曼为本书提供的帮助
以及他一生为真理和正义
不惜牺牲一切的模范事迹
除了加沙骇人听闻的破坏之外
现在真正存在的一种可能性是
冲突将升级 点燃整个地区
并波及世界其他地区
这里的风险再高不过了
现在我很高兴把时间交给一个专家小组
他们的装备再好不过了 可以帮助我们度过这一难关
谢谢
感谢杰米
我只想简单介绍一下我们的工作流程
每位小组成员的发言时间约为六 七分钟
介绍他们对当前危机的看法
然后  我们五人将进行讨论
然后 我们将开放现场提问
也可能向在线观众提出一些问题
在开始之前 我还想补充一点
在我们开始补充杰米的话之前 我只想再补充一件事
我们每天面对的数字似乎深不可测
今天是开斋节
祝那些正在庆祝的以及那些实际上无法庆祝的人们
开斋节快乐
因为这些数字是如此深不可测
如果可以的话 我希望我们所有人都能牢记：
每个生命都是一个完整的世界
每个生命都是
因此 当我们面对这些庞大的数字时
这就是我想让大家在
接受政治分析的同时思考的问题
潜在的后果还会出现
非常感谢各位今晚的光临
我们先从科尔特开始
当然 他也在本书中发表过文章
好的 谢谢你 拉齐娅
最近几周 乔-拜登政府声称
一旦当前的加沙危机结束
它将重振（引述原文）
为以色列-巴勒斯坦冲突建立两国解决方案的共同努力
然而 哈马斯在两国解决方案中
没有一席之地的说法更加强烈
你知道这种说法
哈马斯致力于摧毁以色列国
因此 必须摧毁哈马斯本身
因此 如果我们想在该地区看到任何和平
加沙的种族灭绝就必须继续下去
当然 像这样将以-巴冲突的顽固性归咎于
巴勒斯坦领导人的说法并不新鲜
几十年前 以色列外交部长阿巴-埃本
他声称 引用 巴勒斯坦领导层
从未错过任何一个能够错过和平的机会
正如我在《大洪水》一书中试图证明的那样
现在 这一说法的主要问题是
它与事实记录完全矛盾
实际上 无论是巴勒斯坦解放组织(巴解组织)
还是后来的哈马斯
都以不同程度的清晰度
支持两国解决冲突的方案
而以色列 当然是在美国的单方面支持下
一直拒绝接受这样的决议 支持领土扩张
并在事实上经常诉诸非常血腥的军事攻击
以破坏巴勒斯坦和平进攻的威胁
如果以 1967 年 6
月战争后的 巴解组织为例
巴解组织最初拒绝承认以色列的理由是完全可以理解的
他们不愿意接受一个
通过剥夺和驱赶巴勒斯坦原住民
而在78%的历史巴勒斯坦土地上
建立起来的国家
然而 从 20 世纪 70 年代初开始
特别是 1973 年 10 月战争之后
亚西尔-阿拉法特以及巴勒斯坦核心领导层认识到
要使巴勒斯坦的主张在国际社会眼中合法化
就必须采取承认以色列的这一务实步骤
而早在 1976 年 1 月
巴解组织就在联合国安理会提出要这样做
可以预见的是 美国的反应是否决该决议
以色列则拒绝参加
安全理事会的审议
并在黎巴嫩对巴勒斯坦难民进行了空袭
造成数十人死亡
20世纪70年代末
以色列的这种行为模式越来越明显
美国官员开始注意到
以色列在南黎巴嫩的打击行动与
所谓的巴勒斯坦恐怖威胁关系不大
事实上 一切都有关于试图
将巴勒斯坦人从温和打回极端主义
这一战略的顶点当然是
1982年6月以色列入侵黎巴嫩
由于害怕巴勒斯坦解放组织接受停火
并在一年多的时间里
严格遵守停火并再次倡导谈判
以色列强行进入黎巴嫩
杀害了15,000至20,000名
巴勒斯坦人和黎巴嫩人
跳转到 25 年前 今天的以色列
或者说不是今天的以色列 而是2006年及之后的以色列
在哈马斯的和平进攻威胁下
实施了完全相同的瘟疫计划
哈马斯于2006年1月以改革纲领当选
它很快向华盛顿表示
愿意放弃其臭名昭著的 1988 年宪章
并加入旨在实现两国解决方案的谈判
关键在于这一点
在此后的 15 年里 华盛顿和特拉维夫从未表示过
愿意尝试哈马斯的提议
相反 他们立即采取行动
通过卑鄙和非法的封锁来惩罚哈马斯领导人和加沙人民
当哈马斯威胁要摆脱其作为拒绝派恐怖组织的角色
并寻求加入谈判时
以色列则回归其长期以来的做法
大规模使用军事暴力
正如诺曼详细记录的那样 它在2006年
2008年 2012年和2014年实施了军事行动
几乎每次都是为了至少在一定程度上
破坏巴勒斯坦的和平倡议
因此 当有人提出这个问题时
在哈马斯拒绝参与外交活动
拒绝承认以色列的情况下 以色列如何与哈马斯共存？
它尝试了15年 每一条它想走下去的道路
都被美国和以色列的力量所阻挡
正如我在本章中写到的
底线是这样的：如果不是因为以色列不仅错过
而且积极地拒绝和破坏
拒绝和破坏巴勒斯坦的每一个和平提议
那么 10月7日犯下的罪行
以及正在发生的更大罪行
即以色列在加沙的种族灭绝
就永远不会发生
它们永远不会发生 因为
巴以冲突早就解决了
非常感谢
现在让我们来看看穆因-拉班
非常感谢你 Raziel 感谢 OR Books
组织这次活动并邀请我参加
我认为这是我们应该挥舞书本的时刻
我特别想请你们不仅参阅沃尔特的精彩章节
还要参阅珍妮对该书的精彩介绍
我这一章讲的是 对不起 好吧 我还是靠近麦克风讲吧
是的 我会发言 您也提到了这一点
我的章节是关于当前危机的区域动态
鉴于时间限制 我想关注一个问题
即自10月7日以来突然涌现的许多即时评论家
对他们来说 这是一种信条
即哈马斯在10月7日对以色列
发动袭击的主要动机是
破坏以色列-沙特即将达成正常化协议的前景
我想解释一下为什么情况并非如此
我们不应该再认真对待这些蛊惑人心的人
当他们在乌克兰问题上喋喋不休的时候  在此之前
他们每隔几个月就会对新冠病毒和其他问题推翻自己的论述
一个关键问题是
讨论并不是真正意义上的以色列-沙特正常化协议
即以色列和沙特阿拉伯将
在协议中相互做出主要让步
相反 讨论的是以色列-沙特-美国协定
其中的关键承诺由美国做出
美国作出的主要承诺是
对沙特阿拉伯作出的 具体来说是
以对沙特阿拉伯的安全保证的形式 以及
以交付一个具有铀浓缩能力的核反应堆的形式
仅凭这一点就可以看出
这种协议从一开始就极不可能达成
因为这些都是美国只有
在获得国会批准后才能履行的承诺
由于各种各样的原因
我不会在这里深入讨论
国会极不可能同意
美国对沙特阿拉伯的这种正式承诺
第二 在这样一项协议的范围内
以色列将被要求向巴勒斯坦人作出若干姿态
尽管这些姿态在很大程度上是表面的
但我们面对的是一个
连向巴勒斯坦人做出表面姿态
都做不到的以色列政府
我认为拜登政府在某种程度上
希望这能促使以色列总理
内塔尼亚胡改变执政立场
把一些新法西斯右翼政党换成更加中间派的政党
问题在于 以色列最著名的反对派领导人
亚伊尔-比布特 曾多次公开表示
如果美国承诺向沙特阿拉伯提供核反应堆
他将不会同意与沙特阿拉伯达成任何正常化协议
因此 我的第一点是 无论如何
这种协议都是极不可能的
我的第二点是 即使我错了
即使这样的协议已经迫在眉睫
而且 如果哈马斯已经迫在眉睫
这样的协议即将签署
那么他们发动这次袭击来破坏这样的协议是毫无意义的
因为如果我们回顾一下
阿-以正常化协议的历史
没有任何记录表明 这样的正常化协议
会因为以色列对巴勒斯坦人的政策而被推翻 中止或废除
所以如果你拿1979年
埃及和以色列的主要和平条约来说
它不仅没有受到以色列在
约旦河西岸和加沙地带
持续扩张的影响
甚至没有受到Golta提到的1982年
以色列入侵黎巴嫩的影响
也没有受到萨巴·沙蒂玛大屠杀的影响
同样 1994年的约旦-以色列和平条约
也没有受到以色列后续政策的影响
包括以色列在第二次起义期间
对巴勒斯坦人的残酷镇压
以及最近由由贾里德-库什纳王子
在特朗普政府期间促成的《亚伯拉罕和平协定》
首先维受到2021年爆发的冲突的影响
实际上也未受到当前对加沙地带进行
种族灭绝式袭击的危机的影响
换句话说 哈马斯最希望实现的是
体面地将沙特与以色列的正常化协议
推迟一段体面的时间
埋葬尸体 等等
我认为可以公平地得出结论
哈马斯的领导层会认为那根本不值得付出努力
事实上 如果我们看看哈马斯在
10 月 7 日以及此后发表的声明
他们在几个月前发表了一份重要声明 试图对
10 月 7 日的袭击进行解释 辩解和合理化
他们一次也没有提到沙特阿拉伯
一次也没有提到沙-以关系正常化的前景
他们确实谈到了地区和国际
对塔利班问题的忽视和边缘化
但在更广泛的意义上
而不是他们希望破坏的任何具体协议
我没时间了吗？
我只有一分钟
因此 我最后的看法是 是的
这种地区和国际边缘化以及巴勒斯坦问题的左翼化
以及利用阿-以关系正常化来反对巴勒斯坦人的权利
而不是将其作为争取巴勒斯坦人权利的筹码
这些因素在一般意义上都是其中的因素
我认为 这也解释了为什么
以色列对加沙地带的种族灭绝
已经持续了半年多
而地区和国际上却没有什么反应
非常感谢
谢谢
斯拉沃热·齐泽克
好的
首先 我必须强调 我为能来到这里而感到自豪
很抱歉 如果我从你开始说起 诺曼
我觉得这听起来很可悲
但我是认真的
像你这样的人的存在是反对反犹太主义的最好论据
而非像你这样的人不存在
让我继续
我想简要地向你们报告一下
我在欧洲经历的极其恐怖的内心震惊
也许你们中的一些人知道这件事 但这发生在欧洲
在斯坦福 我参加了一场书展
斯洛文尼亚是主宾国
因此我获准在开幕式上发言
我的发言 我几乎为此感到羞愧
绝对是小心翼翼 有节制的
我说 是的 我谴责哈马斯 谴责一切
我的观点只是巴勒斯坦人也在受苦
你知道发生了什么吗？
现在 他们在每一个德国领土上都有一个特殊的职位
简而言之就是打击反犹太主义的政委
他和另外两个政客上了YouTube——
你可以找到它——他们站起来
就像在过去的共产主义时代一样——
但共产主义者更了解这一点——站起来开始对我大喊大叫
说我是反犹太主义者 我在平等化哈马斯 我是最糟糕的
我是根据语境来理解（加沙） 等等
随后 德国大报《法兰克福汇报》等
对我进行了一系列攻击
其中一个标题非常清楚
哈马斯没有语境
字面上的意思是 你必须理解这一点
你必须回到德国唯心主义形而上学
其思想是这是绝对的原始的深渊的邪恶
没有任何语境可以解释它
当我引用普里莫-列维的话作为回答时
他说分析大屠杀至关重要
而不是说这是邪恶的
我又被攻击了...
所以 让我不要浪费时间
那里还发生了另一件大事
我被指责将书展这一活动政治化
哦 这（本应）是纯粹的文化活动 等等
但对我来说 有五位来自德国的发言者
他们都公开重申了一个动机
那就是完全无条件地支持以色列
而我刚一补充说 巴勒斯坦人也在遭受苦难
我就被指责将年轻人政治化
这让我想到了以色列今天和昨天发生的事情
要知道 那里的哲学教授阿纳德-马塔尔——
现在是一件非常可悲的事情——
因为她发表了一些对以色列来说是既定的 有问题的言论
好吧 他们想在大学里开除她
但有两件事是不祥之兆
首先 学生们抗议她
我在里根时代访问伯克利时也注意到同样的事情
教授——通常是68岁的老人——比学生进步得多
我不知道这里的情况如何 但在整个欧洲
年轻一代的男性大多越来越反动
此外 Anab Matath 的论点
即每种伦理都是基于政治决策的
在这里得到了充分的证明
因为 你看 在法国发生了什么
当他们声称 不
第一批全力支持以色列的人是非政治的
它们只是同情 不
这种判断的去政治化就是最肮脏的政治
让我继续
德国哲学的失败 作为对这些针对我的攻击的回应
与他们一起把我逼入这般境地
尤尔根·哈贝马斯——你可以说是德国的国家哲学家
以及他的两位追随者写了一封公开信
他们没有提到我 但我在那里有我的克格勃特工
他们反对我的观点
宣称要无条件支持 你知道的 常见的废话
以色列是中东唯一的民主社会等等
现在我得出结论 这就是我着迷的地方
甚至是哲学的重要性
你知道哈贝马斯放弃了什么吗？
法兰克福学派第一代伟大的思想家
阿多诺和霍克海默所称的“启蒙的辩证法”
意味着正在发生的恐怖
如殖民主义 古拉格 犹太人大屠杀
并非来自黑暗的中世纪过去的残余
而是欧洲现代性项目内在对立的结果
在哈贝马斯这里 这一点消失了
我们只是需要更多的欧洲启蒙 等等
最后 如果你们愿意 可以向我提问
要知道 我们真的生活在一个悲伤的时代
不仅是德国 我还可以解释一下
德国正在做你能想象到的最不道德的事情
大家都知道
我们的逻辑是 大屠杀是我们干的
所以现在作为与以色列的肮脏交易
我们会说你们是我们的受害者
但作为交换 我们容忍你们今天的罪行
人们喜欢提及今天发生在海地的帮派接管事件
但这不仅发生在海地 甚至发生在世界各地的发达国家
你是否注意到
如果国家权力不直接利用最终属于犯罪团伙的力量
就无法自我复制？
特朗普在这里需要自豪男孩等组织
而在以色列 让我们面对现实吧
西岸的定居者运动是被以色列当权者巧妙利用的非法犯罪团伙
不幸的是 这就是我们今天的处境
用个可悲的词来说 半分钟后
面具就掉下来了
我很震惊 你知道 我的反应就像
在《汤姆和杰瑞》里 当事情发生时 眼睛蹦出来
一个月前 当内塔尼亚胡公开说："从河到海
都是大以色列 "时 我的反应也是如此
因此 以前还比较谨慎的事情 现在都公开进行了
我们正在进入一个新的时代
一个极其危险的时代 而我 天真地认为
虽然他们在欧洲人权问题上是虚伪的
但也许还是有好东西的
我的意思是 现在在加沙发生的事情就是欧洲的死亡
从这个意义上讲 你知道 如果你和一个巴勒斯坦人交谈
他会告诉你 是的 欧洲人权是落在我们身上的绊脚石
最后是诺曼-芬克尔斯坦
谢谢
麦正常么？
好的
谢谢你们邀请我 我要公开感谢
珍妮-斯特恩韦勒和霍尔特
因为无论如何 对我来说
他们两人都代表着相对年轻的一代
对我自己来说 我非常希望
他们能继续这一传统
努力反击 并在斗争中
运用你的智慧以及你的热情
穆因现在是我的老朋友 也是我的同事和战友
我们一起经历了命运的约定 这可能会被标记为一个世界历史事件
我很高兴这是与穆因一起的
尽管我仍然坚持认为他对我的情况来说太过正式了
显然 种族灭绝是没有一线希望的
试图假装有一线希望是有罪的
因此 我不想将其描述为一线希望
我更愿意简单地表达我的观点
即为什么我相信 尽管情况不容乐观
为什么我认为我们所做的是有意义的
以及为什么我们不应该在面对明显不满意的结果时
哪怕一刻也不放松
所以我将回顾过去六个月中
一些让我感到希望的事情
尽管如我所说 对于那些无法达到终点的人来说
这并没有什么安慰
这将是一份非常个性化的名单
正如我们可以证明的那样
在10月7日事件发生后的很早一段时间里
就有一些人迫不及待地试图
将这起种族灭绝案件提交给国际法院审理
我觉得这完全是浪费时间
我无法相信 世界上会有任何国家
愿意为了一个实际上无国籍的民族
一个没有权力和财富的民族
而冒险与美国对抗
因此 当南非站出来的时候 我感到非常震惊
他们站出来不仅仅是一种象征性的姿态
而是以一种非常专业的方式
甚至可以说是深刻的方式站出来的
他们向法庭提交了一份申请书
该申请书就像一份法庭辩护状
其中有数百个脚注
在表述上极为精炼
他们选择了非常令人印象深刻的人代表南非
其中包括我的老朋友 国际法学家约翰-杜加尔德
他是一位非常令人印象深刻的人 即使已经 87 岁高龄
当他走到麦克风前时还有些摇摇晃晃
但他仍然做了非常有力的发言
在许多方面 这是一个由男人 女人 黑人
白人 外国人 南非人组成的出色的代表团
在可能的范围内 他们是在期待一个更美好的世界
他们所做的一切都是为了加沙人民
这些脚注让我印象深刻的一点是
我觉得这些注释有点学术性 但请原谅我
它完全依赖于联合国机构和联合国文件
其中提到了一些人权组织
对于任何长期参与这一事件的人来说
你知道每年都有成百上千
成千上万的报告发布
你不禁翻起白眼 想知道
这些堆积如山的报告
除了可能全世界就五个人会读外
难道不都是在浪费纸张吗？
突然间 那些周而复始地记录着
死亡 饥饿 毁灭的人们的劳动成果
还有那些积满灰尘和蜘蛛网的纸张
突然间变得鲜活起来
对我自己来说 这是一次觉醒
有时你在一个角落里努力工作
认为这都是浪费时间
我为什么要这样做 没有人读它
突然它成为了向国际法院申请的原材料
这是因为它的精确
因为这些组织的中立性
它变得不可抗拒和不可战胜
这就引出了第三点 即国际法院本身发生了什么
我每天都会通过电子邮件或与莫琳交谈
我一直在计算数字
他们不可能让超过六个国家参与这场
貌似有理的种族灭绝
我会说出这些国家的名字 当然 我说 当然
忘了美国 忘了德国 不要浪费你的时间
我还说 忘了澳大利亚吧
我很高兴我错了
我很高兴我的错误是有道理的
比分是 15 比 2
仅有的两名反对者是以色列法官和法庭
以及这位来自乌干达的妇女
我希望她能得到一辆好车和一枚戒指
很显然 她写的东西根本不是她自己写的
这一点非常明显
后来 国际法院的判决是 15 比 2 但这并没有停止
非洲又上交了一次报告
这又是一份非常专业的声明
大量脚注
对加沙人民来说 这已经是第三次了
它停不下来
它不肯罢休
随后 国际法院又就一个类似但不同的问题
审理了一个新的案件
因此 国际法院现在有两起以色列案件
然后 你猜会发生什么？
尼加拉瓜也加入进来 它对德国提出诉讼
指控德国纵容在加沙的种族灭绝
你突然发现 所有这些可能性都为你的倡议打开了大门
他们还没有解决任何确定的问题
但存在可能性和潜在性
我还未读过德文
尼加拉瓜文和德国的回应 但我不得不说
我笑得很开心 因为我确实
听了德国人的一位发言人的发言
德国人喜欢说 哦 我们这样做是为了自己的国家
因为我们有一个特别的人
他因为大屠杀而致力于以色列
这位尼加拉瓜人是一位农民 曾任尼加拉瓜驻荷兰代表
他说 你知道吗
德国人从这场战争中赚了很多钱
他开始查阅所有的军事合同
突然间 面具稍微掉落了一些
这全是关于国家理性 你知道的
使用的是冷静的术语 同时从中赚取大量的金钱
最后 在我结束发言的时候 我要感谢两组人
首先 我发现年轻人
在过去六个月里的反应绝对是英雄式的
完全鼓舞人心 他们不断地站出来
站出来 再站出来
我不记得越战时期有过这样的事
我们也许每六个月或更长时间举行一次大规模示威
也许每三个月一次
但年轻人的坚持和毅力
确实令人鼓舞
我知道 当我去参加示威游行时
我和人群中除我以外的
最年长的人通常相差40岁
我猜他们大多是25岁的年轻人
我最想感谢的一群人是胡塞武装
我觉得非常鼓舞人心的是
据我所知 地球上最贫穷的国家
正如我所理解的 对吗?
在中东 因为我前几天在读到过
在这个星球上 是在中东
他们坚韧不拔 甘愿受苦
这总是让人联想到
最后我想说的是
读过卢梭《卢梭二论》的人都知道
卢梭认为他所说的野蛮人
比文明人更有道德 因为他说
使人人性化的东西
使人成为人的东西 并不是他们的理性
而是他们的怜悯 怜悯是一种自然的能力
怜悯是人类一切积极事物的源泉
他说 你受的教育越多
首先 你会变得越自私；
其次 教育培养了你
为自己不采取行动而找理由的能力
所以他说 一个哲学家向窗外望去
看到有人在他外面的大街上挨打
他只需要闭上耳朵说
随你去死吧 我很安全
这就是哲学家的信条的哲学
但那些不文明的人
他们没有能力将自己对
人类苦难的漠不关心合理化
我一直认为这是一个可信的论点 而且
我认为胡塞武装的行动证明了这一点
昨天 杰米发给我一个视频剪辑
我猜你也看到了 视频里是一些也门渔民
他们反对胡塞武装 他们谈到了自己的苦难
因为美国在这边 伊朗在那边 他们无法捕鱼
但他们说 我们可以证实 他们说
我们不在乎 加沙的人民在受苦
胡塞是他们的敌人
（但）他们说 如果是为了
巴勒斯坦 加沙的受苦人民
我们接受这一切
这是一种美好的情感 对我很有启发
谢谢
非常感谢大家
我想先问问你们每个人
首先还是问你们诺曼吧
因为你们谈到了南非提出的国际法院案件给你们带来的希望
而当时美国国务卿说该案件没有法律依据
类似的说法也出现在以色列提出辩护之后
就在几天前 在参议院面前
美国国防部长说 没有什么可看的
他们没有种族灭绝的证据
鉴于美国的所作所为及其
在过去六个月中非常缓慢的立场转变
你如何看待美国在挽回颜面 深刻改变美国外交政策
改变对以色列的态度方面的可能性？
您如何看待他们迄今为止 最近所说的话？
我认为最大的变化不是在实际政治层面
而是在公众舆论层面
我举两个例子来说明这一点
第一个几乎是令人窒息的时刻是查尔斯·舒默
就当前形势发表了讲话
舒默参议员在美国参议院一直是
以色列最重要的支持者
他反对伊朗协议
我认为他和新泽西州的梅嫩德斯是
唯二反对这项协议的资深民主党参议员
而且他的履历非常糟糕
2010 年 他在一群东正教拉比面前说
我们应该从经济上扼杀加沙 你知道 加沙有一百万儿童
他说 我们应该在经济上扼杀它
他宣读了自己的演讲稿 非常精彩
首先 他将目前僵局的责任完全归咎于
以色列和哈马斯
或者以色列和巴勒斯坦
他一方面说问题在于
内塔尼亚胡和以色列极右翼
另一方面又说问题在于
哈马斯和巴勒斯坦权力机构的腐败
他非常注意平衡
接着 他又试图为以色列不是
殖民定居者国家的说法进行辩护
大约 6 个月前 这甚至还不是
那些精英们讨论的话题
但他突然觉得有必要理性地解释一下
为什么他认为这在历史上是不正确的
接着 他不得不解释
为什么一个国家的想法是错误的
根据国际大屠杀纪念联盟的定义
一个国家被正式视为反犹太主义
有一个国家正式被定义为反犹太国家
舒默做了什么？
舒默参议员首先说
我知道许多有理想的年轻人支持一个国家
他没说他们都是反犹太主义者
他说 他们都是有理想的年轻人
因此 现在你看到民主党的基层
不得不面对一个新的现实
即无论是从历史上还是作为一个犹太国家
以色列从根本上来说都是不合法的
对我来说 这只是在很短的时间内发生的转变
尽管你可以说它已经酝酿了很长时间
这是民意的历史性转变
最后一件事 我不会说太多
我昨天打开了《纽约时报》
他们有一篇文章 讲的是伊朗如何向约旦河西岸
提供所有这些武器 并从那里得到巨额人民币
所以我很好奇
我翻到了这封文章的评论部分
我把它寄给了穆因 他可以再次确认
你知道这封信读起来像什么吗？
为什么伊朗不能向约旦河西岸提供武器?
他们将要占领人民
他们有权武装抵抗
美国凭什么去谈论其他国家的人民提供武器这件事
那里的人民在以此投票 我完全被吓到了
这是《纽约时报》
通常这样的信件会被直接丢弃
突然间 我没记错吧
一个接一个 一个接一个
因此 即使是《泰晤士报》的读者在这一问题上
也已经脱离了合法观点的范围
我想我们是否可以请您谈谈两国方案
与一国方案的问题 因为长期以来
两国方案一直是人们的口头禅
而越来越多的人认为它是空洞的口头禅
当然 如果我们谈论一个国家的解决方案
就会有来自各方的巨大问题
因为这意味着它不再是一个民族主义事件
不再是一个犹太国家
我想知道您如何看待中东内部
在这个问题上的转变
是的 我有三点意见
我认为首先需要指出的是
当西方政客谈论两国解决方案时
我们需要看他们的行动 而不是他们的言辞
对他们来说 两国解决方案只是一种转移视线的把戏
这是烟雾弹
这是在用语言转移人们
对他们行动的注意力
因为他们的行动正在破坏任何解决方案
尤其是结束以色列占领的前景
因为这种占领正在通过
西方国家的积极或消极支持而被巩固
第二个问题是 两国方案
是否仍然可行 或者是否可行?
我曾就此写过文章 我认为从实际情况来看
两国解决方案仍然是可行的
以色列撤至 1967 年边界
并且 拆除定居点和对难民问题的公正解决
从原则上说 仍然是可行的
我认为 一个有用的比较方法是
将以色列在西岸的地位与1915年英国在爱尔兰的地位
1950年法国在阿尔及利亚的地位
1985年埃塞俄比亚在厄立特里亚的地位
1990年印尼在东帝汶的地位进行比较
我认为在所有这些案例中你会发现 对不起
外国的存在在许多方面
比以色列在被占领土上的存在更加根深蒂固
现在 第三点变成了 好吧 如果它确实切实可行
那么在过去六个月里发生了什么？
在这里 我想说的是
对于许多以前认为这很实用
但现在也认为不再可取的人来说
问题就变成了这样
在一个非理性 种族灭绝
种族隔离政权继续存在的情况下 中东能有持久的和平吗？
或者 作为中东和平的先决条件
这个政权及其关键机构需要被摧毁吗?
我认为 这些问题越来越多地
被提出来进行讨论
我认为这方面没有简单的答案
我最后要说的是 我的分析
绝非基于所谓奥斯陆进程的失败
我认为奥斯陆是 1945 年以来最成功的外交进程之一
原因很简单 那就是奥斯陆从来都不是为了结束占领
这与两国解决方案无关
它从来都不是为了建立一个独立的巴勒斯坦国
而是为了重新制定和
巩固以色列对巴勒斯坦人的永久控制
从这个意义上说 它是成功的
科尔曼 你想回来回应一下吗？
我个人认为
现在根本不是谈论解决方案的时候
首先 没有一个有代表性的
巴勒斯坦组织可以与之谈判
以色列的政治光谱是--
我不会随便用这个词 我以前没用过
但我不会随便用--
以色列的政治光谱是疯狂的
从右翼到极右翼 再到极右翼
没有中间 也没有左边 这只是一个事实问题
所以没什么好商量的
可以说 2000年左右的《奥斯陆协议》
和《戴维营协议》
可以说 在那些年里 你仔细看看我所掌握的谈判情况
他们一直在争论百分比的问题
因此 巴拉克说 我们希望
保留80%的非法定居者
我们希望在任何最终定居点保留80%的非法定居者
埃尔默说我们要保留 87%
巴勒斯坦人说你们可以保留 60%
以色列人说 我们想保留西岸约 10%的土地
巴勒斯坦人说 我们会让你们保留 2% 的约旦河西岸
我不是说他们很接近
差距仍然存在 也许不是鸿沟 但差距很大
但我们说的是百分比
但现在的以色列政府
我们不能从他们那里得到一个扫帚间或一个面包箱给巴勒斯坦人
所以 现在没有讨论的余地
没有任何可以进行论证的两方立场
第二点 在我看来 我们必须实事求是
战争可能会持续很长时间
乌克兰战争已经过去两年多了
然后你可以看看越南战争 或者看看第二次世界大战
大约六个月后 我不想这么说
但我认为我们很有可能仍然更接近开始 而不是结束
因为如果你读了以色列的声明
你读了分析 就像我昨晚
读了一个来自JINSA的分析
它是犹太新保守主义疯子组织之一
他们说 除非哈马斯遭到绝对
彻底 明确的失败
以色列取得绝对 彻底
明确的胜利 否则不可能有任何结果
而另一方面 真主党等组织则表示
我们不会接受哈马斯的彻底失败
我们将尽一切必要的努力
阻止哈马斯彻底失败
因此 我认为我们离结束目前的局面可能还很遥远
现在谈论解决方案毫无意义
斯拉瓦 让我们谈谈需要进行的道德清算
即使我们接受诺曼的说法
这种情况也会持续很久很久
事实上 它已经发展到了今天的地步
6 个月内有 33 000 人丧生
与 2021 年相比 这似乎是不可想象的
科塔 帮我算算
2021年有多少人丧生？
所以是 1600 或类似的数字
最大的一次 "铸铅行动 是 1200 人 1400 人
护刃行动造成 2 200 人丧生
所以我们 你知道 完全不同
因此 鉴于西方世界继续自视甚高
尽管这种思想
在我们眼前分崩离析
但它仍继续把自己视为
世界上发生的一切的道德仲裁者
我们该如何看待对未能保护加沙成千上万无辜民众的行为
进行道德清算的必要性?
至关重要的问题
我只想简单说几句 以免迷失方向
首先是关于 3 万人死亡的问题
我认为这不仅仅是一个数据问题
就连西方媒体也不否认这一数据
但是 特别是在德国
但也在其他国家 有一种解释模式
而在德国 这已经合法化了
即使是相对温和的文化部长
我会称她为野蛮部长克劳迪娅·罗奇 她明确表示 她说
你可以严肃地——我对此有如汤姆和杰瑞般的反应——她说
是的 我们可以谈论巴勒斯坦人的苦难
但我们应该明确最终是哈马斯对此负责
这就好像 哈马斯正在进行一场大规模的自杀行动
而以色列却莫名其妙地把上帝扯了进来 这必须改变
而且 正如指出的那样 改变这种公众认知是至关重要的
例如 我们应该坚持以色列——好吧
我们听到哈贝马斯等人的说法 唯一的民主国家——对不起
但一个月前或内塔尼亚胡反对两国解决方案时
这意味着从河到海的大以色列
他说这是唯一的民主解决方案
因为 我不知道这是否属实
但他写了一些统计数据
现在以色列那里的犹太人中几乎有90% 90%反对它
对不起 但如果你考虑到以色列控制的所有区域
几乎是五五开
犹太人可能只比巴勒斯坦人多一点点
她甚至没有提到 你看 这实际上是种族隔离
那么我们能做什么呢？
还有一件事 也许沿着
你通常强调公众舆论的实际路线
会发生一些事情 就像我知道的那样
也许我得用我在斯洛文尼亚的
一些影响力稍微推动一下
但我从可靠消息来源得知
现在到六月底 七月 西班牙 爱尔兰
而且这很好 我的小影响力起作用了 斯洛文尼亚
好吧 虽然不是世界上最大的声音 将公开承认巴勒斯坦
而且这些你通常提到的小迹象
甚至连我不信任的人也提到了这一点
戴维·卡梅伦 在某个时候 提到也许我们应该
英国外交大臣
是啊 是啊
你知道现在
英国的政治局势如何吗？
你们有一个很大很大的中央右翼政党
这就是所谓的工党
然后 又有一些疯狂的右翼政党
好吧 但是 对不起 让我继续说
因此 我想说的是 正如你所指出的
我们现在必须迈出下一步
现在 谈论巴勒斯坦人的苦难已经合法化了
现在我们进入下一阶段
那么 这种痛苦意味着什么呢？
逻辑是 如果 是的 你必须同情
你会放那些愚蠢的降落伞 但是这意味着什么？
我认为其中有一个想法
对我来说是这种情况的最佳象征
我在大型媒体中发现了它
这是一张相同的照片 你从加沙看到的 前面是以色列的炸弹
由美国制造的炸弹 落在加沙 摧毁建筑物
而就在后面 带着食物的降落伞也在下降
这就是问题所在
最后 请允许我简短地说一句
你知道我们必须在哪一点上努力
这些禁令是如何存在的 在哪里被允许去演说？
当我在法兰克福说我说的话时
最令我恶心的是 有几十个人 强硬派的德国人
私下里走过来 真的小心翼翼地四处张望
然后对我耳语 你知道 基本上我同意你的观点
只是现在不是说这些话的合适时机
我的回答当然是 我知道你是什么意思
合适的时机将是在说这些话毫无意义的时候
而现在 说这些话是有意义的
所以你知道吗 我真的在想
如果我也对你说这些话 你最终会同意吗
我不相信他们
但是 例如 你们可能都知道我是谁
如果你们聪明的话 还包括Sinbad
Moser的前老板
但有一个人叫 我想叫阿米·阿亚顿
好的
他现在已经退休了
一旦你退休了 你就可以说很多话
所以 他写了一篇评论或接受了采访
他说唯一的解决方案是
允许巴勒斯坦人拥有政治主体性
甚至提出了一个非常实际的建议 释放马文·巴尔古提等人
但如果你在德国说这话 会是什么情况
作为一个前警察或辛贝特的主管
我认为 如果你在德国说这话 几乎会被逮捕
所以 不仅仅是
在这样的地方说这些话是一回事等等
在这一点上 斗争是有效的
并且逐渐改变公众认知的斗争不是没有希望的
我只想说 你没有回答
关于你的道德准则的问题
我从未回答过这个问题
好吧 那我继续
我想知道你能否谈谈你是如何解释在你的文章中
你如此仔细地记录和记录了这个事实
即每一个哈马斯愿意参与并愿意表明
其努力保持温和或参与和平进程的实例
然而 大多数人在了解正在发生的事情时
所吸收的叙述
却是与西方政府和特别是以色列所框定的
（与你文章中）完全相反的叙述
你如何解释这种情况
即人们对你详细记录的内容缺乏了解？
诺姆·乔姆斯基写了一本关于这个问题的书 《制造共识》
事实上 西方媒体普遍受制于
大企业的利益
而且复述美国国家意见 符合它们的既得利益
因此它们不愿意告诉美国人和更广泛的西方人
关于以色列对加沙的所作所为的真相
不仅仅是自10月7日以来
而是在这之前一再发生的事情
我可以举一个例子 铸铅行动
关于铸铅行动的媒体叙述通常是将其描述为
以色列对哈马斯火箭袭击进行自卫的行为
但实际上铸铅行动是
以色列违反停火协议的产物
停火协议于2008年6月签署 以色列官员坦率地承认
哈马斯激进分子严格遵守了停火协议
并且带来了——我现在引用一位以色列国防官员的话——
给加沙周边的以色列社区
带来了很大程度的和平与安宁
停火协议的内容是
哈马斯停止发射火箭 他们做到了
而以色列则将解除其非法和压制性的封锁
事实并非如此
勉强缓解了一下
11月4日 对此 诺曼
做了最详细的记录 但在11月4日
当美国人还沉浸在总统选举的喜悦中时
以色列突袭加沙 打死六名巴勒斯坦武装分子
这时 火箭弹开始飞来 以色列开始轰炸加沙
12 月 19 日
停火协议（为期 6 个月）到期
几天之内 哈马斯通过
卡特中心相关人员
挪威等欧洲政府以及联合国
向以色列提出
恢复之前的停火协议
即巴勒斯坦人遵守而以色列不断违反的停火协议
两天后 12月21日
以色列内阁召开会议 决定轰炸加沙
并在那里发动一次大规模行动
事实上 自 2006 年以来 他们已经计划了多年
他们在黎巴嫩被真主党羞辱了
不仅在12月21日的内阁会议上
决定要开始轰炸加沙
他们还决定谎报何时开始轰炸
齐皮·利夫尼会见了当时的埃及总统
穆巴拉克 并让他知道
直到12月28日星期天
以色列才会决定如何处理加沙不断升级的局势
然而在12月27日上午11点30分
以色列向小小的加沙投下了100吨炸弹
据人权组织称 在几分钟内
他们杀死了多达300名巴勒斯坦人
若说10月7日是以色列-巴勒斯坦冲突历史上
最血腥的一天
当然 "铸铅行动 "开始的几分钟
是最血腥的几分钟
当时的以色列前总理兼国防部长埃胡德·巴拉克夸耀说
他在铸铅行动的开始几分钟内
杀死了350名恐怖分子
当然 以色列随后进行的行动
被国际特赦组织称为
加沙的22天的死亡与破坏
杀死了约1400名巴勒斯坦人 其中大约80%是平民
所以 当你听到有人谈论10月7日
人们说哈马斯必须被摧毁
因为它违反了停火协议并犯下了可怕的暴行
我不认为有什么理由不能将同样的论点应用于
以色列及其在铸铅行动开始时所做的事情
不仅仅是铸铅行动
还有2012年的防御支柱行动
还有2014年的行动
我想继续讨论一下
我们迄今听到的一些评论
其实 我只是想研究一下--我不会把你也扯进来的
穆因--政府和人民之间的关系
在中东 在我看来
不管海湾地区的专制国家
和绝对君主制等进行什么操作
它们之间的关系都是相互依存的
这些国家和政府与西方的关系
与街头的阿拉伯人之间的距离
是如此之远
这些国家和政府需要在
阿拉伯人对巴勒斯坦和巴勒斯坦人的感情
以及什么可能适合那些掌权者之间找到平衡
是的 我的意思是
我们经常被告知
我们经常被告知阿拉伯世界没有民主
因为某种落后的文化 落后的宗教 落后和偏见
好吧 我们来举个例子
巴勒斯坦人 你甚至不需要去阿拉伯世界
你有一个由西方支持和支撑的巴勒斯坦权力机构
其合法性在其自身人民中正好相反
它在自己人民中的信誉
和合法性越低
得到的西方支持就越多…
它实际上是由以色列和西方支撑起来的
当然 你知道 这些并不是阿拉伯世界缺乏民主的唯一原因
但它们绝对是任何分析的核心
还说 哦 阿拉伯人只是想把自己的弊端归咎于西方
再来看看巴勒斯坦的例子
2006 年 巴勒斯坦人举行了一次选举
我相信 卡特中心已对此进行了认证
不仅完全自由公正 而且我认为
是卡特中心所监督的所有选举中最自由公正的一次
不管人们怎么看待哈马斯
哈马斯在那次选举中赢得了胜利
而西方的反应是实施封锁
实施封锁 妖魔化
去合法化 以及对加沙地带的
反复军事袭击
正是这些行动导致了我们今天正在经历的
对加沙地带巴勒斯坦人的种族灭绝性攻击
所以 别跟我说什么
西方正在寻找民主伙伴
每当出现一丝民主伙伴的迹象时
他就被消灭了
我只想读一下库尔特文章中的一段话
他引用了希拉里-克林顿担任参议员时的一段话
如果我们要推动选举
我们就应该确定谁会获胜
准确无误
我想继续沃尔特和穆因的工作
在我看来 显然我们可以对此有不同意见
当你对他人的行为进行道德评判时
在我看来 你还必须审视在作出决策的背景下
有哪些可用的选择
正如穆因所指出的 对加沙实施了一次残酷的封锁
它实际上始于1991年
从那时起就开始封锁了
然后在2006年哈马斯赢得选举后升级
并在2007年再次升级
在那时 封锁的残酷过程开始了
这使得加沙变成了经济学家所称的“人类垃圾堆”
现在 加沙有200万人
其中70%是1948年及其后裔的难民
其中一半是儿童 超过一百万的儿童
他们由于封锁的结果
再次引用这个说法
变成了“人类垃圾堆”
这就是所谓的社会经济背景
没有人能进去 也没有人能出来
10 月 7 日冲破加沙大门的大多数年轻人
都出生在那个垃圾堆里
生活在那个垃圾堆里
10月6日的情况也是如此
他们会死在垃圾堆里
这就是社会经济背景
现在 库尔特对政治背景进行了补充
在此期间 哈马斯曾多次试图
通过外交途径解决冲突
他们的建议完美吗？
不
他们是否需要进行大量的
激烈谈判才能达成和解？
在我看来 是的 但肯定有合理的建议
它们是试图通过外交途径解决冲突的基础
所有这些外交提议都被断然拒绝了
甚至没有被承认为提议
那么 现在巴勒斯坦人还剩下什么选择？
有一个选择 我不得不尴尬地承认
我曾在几年的所有演讲中推广这个选择
我认为非暴力的公民抵抗的可能性和选择是可行的
2018年3月30日 这是一个民众倡议
最初并不是由哈马斯发起的
这是一个民众倡议
他们尝试了非暴力的公民抵抗 称为“大返回游行”
联合国有一份很好的报告
报告长达 250 页 单行距
即使按照联合国的标准
也是非常详尽的
虽然没有戈德斯通报告那么大 但它是一份非常重要的报告
这是一份非常详细的报告
该报告用了很大篇幅来描述
"回归大游行 "中 那些游行者的遭遇
仅提供关键事实 首先
他们描述游行的开始 人们将会记得
一开始 这是一个喜庆的节日
有唱歌的 有跳舞的 还有类似马戏团的表演
人们对这一前景的可能性和潜力充满热情
以色列做了什么？
它将最好的狙击手一字排开
这是加沙周边最好的狙击手
然后 报告详细介绍了
这些狙击手的所作所为
他们援引以色列政府的话说
每一颗子弹都落在了预定地点
这里不存在像 WCK 那样的失误和错误
每颗子弹都落在了预定的地方 明白吗？
因此 报告说以色列有条不紊
有计划 有预谋地设置了狙击手
它以儿童为目标
以医务人员为目标 以记者为目标
它针对的是残疾人 它针对的是双截肢者
它针对的是坐在轮椅中的人
他瞄准了距离边界围栏300米的
拄着拐杖的人
现在任何了解非暴力的人都知道
作为一种斗争方法
它只有在引发旁观者 非参与者
作为施暴者或受害者的反应时才能奏效
马丁·路德·金的非暴力运动的全部意义在于
他说如果我们展示这个系统中根深蒂固的暴力
我们就能唤起同情
并引发联邦政府和北方的行动
要想展示这一制度中根深蒂固的暴力
唯一的办法就是走出去示威
他们会带着狗出来 带着消防水龙带出来
有时还会带着枪出来
然后人们应该做出反应
如果我们的联邦政府不做出反应
如果北方不做出反应 那么所有人都会死
非暴力是死路一条
而事实上 当以色列把儿童 医护人员
记者和残疾人作为攻击目标时 却没有人做出反应
我不得不承认 连巴勒斯坦团结运动都没有做出反应
所以我不得不尴尬地说 我之后感到羞愧
因为我曾与一些有职位的人保持联系
我是那个提出建议的人
但那完全是彻底的失败
所以我说 我们来到了 10 月 6 日的夜晚
外交 行不通
非暴力的公民抵抗是行不通的
我愿意接受穆因的话
因为他的知识比我渊博得多
他说 沙特的协议并不会真正发生
但我确信穆因会同意我的看法 很多人认为它会发生
因此他们认为
整个阿拉伯-以色列冲突会在
加沙人民的头颅上得到解决
海湾国家 沙特
以色列和美国之间会永远幸福美满
加沙人民 他们将在集中营里
受尽折磨 走向死亡
这就是他们的命运和未来
除非有人能向我展示他们没有利用的选项
否则在那时他们还有什么选择
我个人承认
在10月7日发生了重大暴行
但我个人发现很难谴责10月7日发生的事情
即使我承认有暴行发生
好吧 稍等一下
因为我们大概还有20分钟 我想把讨论交给观众
我会给你机会回应 斯拉沃热
我真的看不到我们身上的灯光
但是是的 我可以 如果你们举手 那就太好了
是的 你们太害羞了
那边有一个吗？
你能站起来吗？
当然
对不起 有人吗？
请起立
有麦克风吗？
你有麦克风吗？
这重要吗？
我认为 如果你谈论它
你好 谢谢
我想回到以色列的政治问题上来
所以你谈到了右派 中右派和极右派
我的意思是 我们也看到了一种
反对内塔尼亚胡的抗议运动正在增长
目的是让人质回家
但这并没有太多提及巴勒斯坦人
你知道 我认为完全没有
如果有的话 也是很少
我想问的是 如果我们假设支持巴勒斯坦的全球运动继续增长
而以色列内部的运动也许也以某种方式增长
但却是以一种真正巩固一个
不那么极右翼的以色列的方式增长的话
你会怎么做？
你如何处理这七百万以色列人口的问题
他们似乎拒绝接受
他们的社会存在
根本性的压迫和错误？
这是专门向某个人提问的么？
我的意思是 诺曼
我很想听听你的想法 还有其他人的看法
当然
我更愿意先听穆因的意见
我认为这个社会的问题
你可以把它想象成一个在瓷器店里横冲直撞的被宠坏的孩子
而店主没有要求孩子的父母
支付损坏瓷器的费用
反而告诉父母这个孩子有多可爱
并请他们再多打碎一些
我认为我们需要对以色列社会表现出一些理解
如果你被允许逍遥法外这么久
如果完全的豁免是默认设置
你不能真的期望这个社会会有不同的行为
人们谈论以色列的和平运动有多么小
虽然它确实非常小
但从某种意义上说
这本身就是一个奇迹
考虑到这个社会与其西方支持者的关系
以及它在对待巴勒斯坦人民时所享有的绝对豁免权
包括种族灭绝
即使是这一点 也得到了西方的积极支持
因此 就你所说的这些抗议活动而言
你知道 在 10 月 7 日之前
曾有过一场声势浩大的抗议运动
反对内塔尼亚胡政府的立法议程
司法改革？
没错 就是所谓的司法改革
那个抗议运动的领导人积极阻止任何
关于以色列-巴勒斯坦关系的讨论
用这个委婉语来说
将其排除在抗议运动之外
现在 抗议仅仅是为了反对政府与哈马斯达成协议
以便释放被俘人员
但除此之外 据我所知
抗议运动并没有一个政治议程
来改变以色列-巴勒斯坦关系的性质
因此 如果你想改变以色列社会 就不要盯着以色列
看看那些支持以色列的人
还有那些教导以色列社会什么都可以做
甚至包括种族灭绝的人
根本问题在于 永远不会有问责
免责成为默认状态
诺曼 你之前提到的查克·舒默的评论
不也是一个问题吗？
这种普遍的看法认为
只要把内塔尼亚胡赶下台
情况就会好转
但却没有考虑到以色列根深蒂固的结构性观点
以及以色列人的意识和心理
这里有几个评论要说
首先 我完全同意你的看法 这不仅仅是内塔尼亚胡的战争
就像这不仅仅是普京的战争一样
在两者的情况下 这都是精英阶层的共识
不仅仅是内塔尼亚胡一个人的决定
就以色列而言 我不太愿意谈俄罗斯
因为我不了解民众的情绪
就俄罗斯而言 是整个国家
不好意思 就以色列而言 是整个社会
如果你看民意调查数据
大约90%的以色列人认为 或者88%
认为以色列使用了足够的武力或不足的武力
大约40%的人认为以色列在加沙使用的武力不足
只有大约12%的人
对以色列的所作所为有不同看法
所以我不同意 我同意你的看法
我认为把这描述为内塔尼亚胡的战争是不正确的
我也不认为舒默参议员的说法是准确的
好像如果有选举
有一个更好的人选
也许是甘茨 他在竞选时
就是以他在2014年对加沙造成的破坏作为竞选纲领的
那是他的竞选视频
所以我不能说我对这一点乐观
认为这只是内塔尼亚胡和少数几个人的问题
我要说的是 虽然我并不乐意这么说 但我认为现在试图改变
以色列人的态度是徒劳的
就像在民权运动期间
试图改变南方白人的态度是徒劳的一样
它需要外部力量
包括引入联邦军队来取消南方的种族隔离
在南方 有少数白人
对正在发生的事情有所保留
他们真诚地反对 但只是极少数
我不认为你可以期望
改变所有穆因所描述的那些原因
他没有提到意识形态方面的内容
这是一种致命的结合 包括犹太人劣等感
和我们的劣等感——实际上是我们的动物性
而不是劣等感——还有这些
不同层次的意识形态的丑恶
使得要改变以色列人的态度非常困难
我得说 因为我想公正地看待这些事情
可以说有两个
在20世纪非常丑陋的历史中 可以说上帝创造的地球上
最种族主义和帝国主义的两个国家是
1930年代的德国和日本
他们在二战期间犯下的罪行
简直是十足的暴行
我们都知道德国人的罪行
而日本人杀害了大约2600万中国人
这是日本人在亚洲发动的一场非常丑陋的战争
但国家变了 德国变了 日本也变了
所以我不相信这些原罪的概念
但我同意 我已经开始同意莫琳的观点
即有必要对以色列社会进行认真的改革
如何发生 如何展开 我也说不清楚
但它现在真的是个丑陋的地方
而且已经丑陋了很久
我得承认
当我读到现在的报道时 这些报道
现在 现在 针对以色列 这真的太可怕了
以色列把自己置于这样的境地
以色列把自己置于这样的境地 我天性上总是支持弱者
我几乎为它对自己所做的一切感到难过 因为这真的很可怕
而这些人 他们甚至不知道自己做了什么
这就像是对堕胎的声明
也许整个想法从一开始就是错的
也许一开始就是错的
但是 美国一开始就有很多问题
美国找到了一种方法
虽然它并没有让这里变得伟大 但确实需要消灭原住民
你不能忘记这一点
但美国似乎有某种自我改革的能力
而我不知道以色列该怎么办
让我们再问几个问题
我确定
后面举起了一只手
是的 我想跟进一下
我的意思是 伊兰-庞贝谈到了
特拉维夫的以色列和中央的以色列
我的意思是 在巴勒斯坦问题上
以色列是一个非常团结的社会
但从内部看 这是一个极端两极分化的社会
以色列人认为自己生活在一个高度两极分化的社会中
我认为 如果你了解以色列人
特别是特拉维夫的以色列人
自10月7日以来 尤其是2023年
你会听到这样的想法：
在特拉维夫的以色列中 有一种想法是
我们可以把巴勒斯坦问题边缘化 不需要解决它
我们可以继续生活在一个看似正常的社会里
在特拉维夫的咖啡馆里吃羊角面包
2023年 首先是所谓的民主危机
然后是10月7日的事件
在整个特拉维夫的以色列社会中
对在以色列生活的未来失去了投资信心
突然之间 很多人开始说这里没有未来了
我们将不断生活在来自哈马斯 真主党
和伊朗的暴力威胁之下 而这些人原本是那种人道
自由 开明的以色列的世界大使 对吗？
我的意思是说
这些人都是有良好教育的专业人士和知识分子
他们参加会议 并把自己说成是
生活在一个正常的国与国之间的国家
在那些人中存在一种大规模的运动
即对国家项目的撤资
很多人说要离开 也有很多人说要搬回欧洲
这也开始发生了 这是一个特定的问题
我的意思是评论真的非常有趣 是的
所以问题只是你认为这是一个主要因素
因为我知道人们说
我的意思是以色列社会在巴勒斯坦人的问题上已经无法改革
但你认为这是一个重要的推动因素
是的 未来的事件
先生 你要接这个话题吗？
不 我想换一个方向
好的
我能简单回答一下吗？
请说吧
这就是说 我不会假装比你更了解这个问题
假设你的观察是正确的
我认为这使问题变得比看上去更加复杂
因为这涉及到自我改革的能力
根本就不存在
我看到其他人的手也在举
我只想问小组成员一个问题
您认为这场冲突
在该地区蔓延的可能性有多大？
以色列是否有兴趣扩大这场冲突？
穆欣 你在 MC 中提到了这一点
你能重复一下问题吗？
是的 当然
地区战争升级符合以色列的利益吗？
这种可能性有多大？
我认为以色列希望地区冲突升级
因为它看到了将美国直接卷入冲突的机会
从以色列的角度来看 伊朗与其对手之间的冲突
是以色列挑起伊朗-美国直接对抗的理想局面
我只想简单说一下 你知道伊朗最近袭击了--
对不起 是以色列袭击了伊朗驻大马士革领事馆
显然 伊朗人已经向美国人发出信息
如果美国人成功实现永久停火
换句话说 结束以色列
在加沙地带的战争
那么 对伊朗人来说 这件事就结束了
如果美国人失败了
那么伊朗人已经决定 为了威慑以色列
他们将直接对以色列领土发动攻击
不是通过他们的同盟民兵 而是直接从伊朗领土发动攻击
因此 换句话说
如果美国人做出不结束战争的选择
这将是一个政策决定
而伊朗人则会继续威胁
我们可能会看到一个非常重要的
我只想重申我之前说过的话
如果美国强制执行永久停火
以换取伊朗不采取任何报复行动
那么问题是
哈马斯将能够宣布胜利
但以色列不会接受这一点
以色列决心取得绝对 明确
彻底的胜利 让哈马斯彻底失败
这就是第二个问题
目前 由于真主党的影响
以色列北部约有 10 万人流离失所
以色列对此也不满意
它会给真主党放行吗？
我个人认为 但我们可以有不同意见
他比我更清楚 我个人是不相信的
还有第三个问题 也就是库尔特提到的问题
打破永久停火非常容易
你们可以同意永久停火 以色列也可以同意永久停火
正如库尔特在 2008 年 6 月指出的那样
然后 当以色列想要战争时 就挑衅
挑衅 再挑衅 然后就有了战争
每个人都忘记了是谁挑衅
正如米尔肯所说 这本身就是一种防御
因此 就我个人而言
我不认为任何宣布的永久停火有任何意义或价值
因为纵观历史
停火很容易被打破
我能问一下科尔特
关于诺曼的观点吗？
关于以色列一次又一次宣布
要彻底消灭哈马斯的可行性
因为你在你的文章中提到了这一点
哈马斯是多方面的
它是一个社会运动 是一个民兵组织
是一个政治运动 也只是一个理念
嗯 简短的回答是
以色列完全不可能消灭哈马斯 即使
我们接受——我并不接受——消灭哈马斯
在道德上是无可非议的 但实际上这不会发生
哈马斯不仅以加沙地带为基地
它的基地遍布被占领土内外
此外 即使你能摧毁
哈马斯的军事能力
以色列声称 它已经或多或少地消灭了
哈马斯在加沙地带北部的军事能力
即使它入侵拉法 你知道
带着辛瓦尔和其他哈马斯领导人被砍下的头颅回来
它不会对巴勒斯坦人的不满来源
做出任何改变 我们一直在谈论这一点
这是显而易见的
几十年的占领 种族隔离 屠杀
即使从这些灰烬中产生的东西不自称为哈马斯
也会是同样的问题
我想我们得结束了
除非有人有紧急问题要问
有人举手
我真的看不到房间后面
你为什么不问这个问题呢？
我有一个问题
好的
我是
我想知道 在你看来
为什么尼加拉瓜对德国提起诉讼 而不是对美国提起诉讼
因为美国似乎是以色列的主要支持者
无论是武器支持还是财政支持？
我想是因为尼加拉瓜在中美洲 而德国在欧洲
我想直接到房间后面去
有一只手举起来了吗？
不是那个问特拉维夫问题的人
因为你已经问过一个问题了
对不起 先生
在前面 这里
对你们任何人来说
美国和以色列之间
那种完全豁免 完全容忍和支持的关系有任何改变的可能吗？
我的意思是 公众舆论已经发生了很大变化
这种情况今后是否有可能发生任何变化
哪怕是很小的变化？
谁想谈一谈这个？
我认为 诺曼和其他人所谈到的变化
具有深远的政治意义
但要让它们对你提出的问题类型产生影响
还需要时间
如果你问的是短期问题
我的回答是拜登 布林肯 内塔尼亚胡
他们不会被追究责任
他们将逍遥法外
不幸的是 世界就是这样运转的
但话说回来 林肯的孙子们
每当他们想研究21世纪加沙的种族灭绝时
他们会知道
任何不将其祖父作为主角的研究
都是不完整的
不幸的是 我认为这可能就是问责的范围
卡里姆-汗还在装饰他的圣诞树
国际刑事法院不会介入
国际法院可以做出明确的裁决
但却无法执行
国际体系目前的结构方式
遗憾的是
没有你所要求的问责制或罪犯
这是一个多么灰暗的结尾
但我们不得不就此结束
买这本书并继续讨论吧
非常感谢你们的到来
谢谢
我还没有对小组成员说谢谢
我真是太失礼了
诺曼-芬克尔斯坦 穆恩-拉瓦尼 斯拉沃伊-齐泽克
和科尔特·刘易斯
非常感谢
谢谢